<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Python: Colors and Pixels on Nuevo Foundation Workshops</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-pixel/colors_and_pixels/</link><description>Recent content in Python: Colors and Pixels on Nuevo Foundation Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 13:24:17 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-pixel/colors_and_pixels/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Import an image module</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-pixel/colors_and_pixels/load_image_module/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-pixel/colors_and_pixels/load_image_module/</guid><description>Setting up the project To get started let’s start with importing a module. What does that mean? To do fun stuff with images, we need to unlock some functions to use. To get these functions we need to import a module. In this case if we import the module Pillow, we can use some functions that will help us modify images.
Firstly, let’s delete everything in the main.py file. Then, add the following statements:</description></item><item><title>Open an image</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-pixel/colors_and_pixels/open-image/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-pixel/colors_and_pixels/open-image/</guid><description>To change an image, we must open an image. We can use the Pillow Image module we just imported in the setup. Let’s first find some images to open. Find an image of your choice and download it. Once you have downloaded it, navigate back to your repl.it window and upload your image by clicking on the three dots and selecting ‘upload file’.
For example, to upload the cat.jpg file:</description></item><item><title>Basics of colors</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-pixel/colors_and_pixels/basic-of-colors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-pixel/colors_and_pixels/basic-of-colors/</guid><description>Basics of Colors While going through all kinds of pictures online, have you ever questioned how those pictures get their colors? Actually, computers have RGB mode to represent colors.
RGB format In Python, we follow a specific format when defining colors: (R, G, B), where &amp;ldquo;R&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;G&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;B&amp;rdquo; are all integers. &amp;ldquo;R&amp;rdquo; represents some amount of red, &amp;ldquo;G&amp;rdquo; represents some amount of green, and &amp;ldquo;B&amp;rdquo; represents some amount of blue.</description></item><item><title>Pixels on an Image</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-pixel/colors_and_pixels/pixel-on-image/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-pixel/colors_and_pixels/pixel-on-image/</guid><description>Pixels Pixels are a small area of color on a display screen. Images are formed by pixels on the screen. We can manipulate pixels by changing the RGB Value, which are essentially changing the value of red, green and blue color on each pixels. When we see the an image on the screen, it is made of huge numbers of tiny pixel. Each tiny pixels has its only unique position and color it displays.</description></item><item><title>Access pixels on image</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-pixel/colors_and_pixels/access-pixel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-pixel/colors_and_pixels/access-pixel/</guid><description>More about pixels We have already learned how to make a pure color image using pixels and change a pixel on the image. Now, we will learn how to identify pixels in existing images.
For information about how to use lists and tuples in Python see more on these pages: Data Structure Get image data # Remember to import Image from PIL import Image Image.size Image.size[0] Image.size[1] Image.</description></item></channel></rss>