<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Linux Basics on Nuevo Foundation Workshops</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/</link><description>Recent content in Linux Basics on Nuevo Foundation Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using Virtual Machines Part 1</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/vbox-setup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/vbox-setup/</guid><description>So you can help us, we are providing you with a copy of the hacked computer as a virtual machine.
What is a virtual machine? A virtual machine (commonly called a vm) is a computer file (called an image), that behaves like an actual computer. In other words, creating a computer within a computer. It runs in a window, much like any other program. This gives you the same experience on a vm as you would on a regular computer.</description></item><item><title>Using Virtual Machines Part 2</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/vm-import-setup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/vm-import-setup/</guid><description>Good work on getting the host environment ready! Now let&amp;rsquo;s load the image of the hacked computer as a vm.
What is an image Images come in a variety of types. We have photographs, which are images. The images in computers are similar. Both are copies from a single point in time. This means what we will be working with is a copy of the computer that has been acting weird.</description></item><item><title>Starting up the Virtual Machine</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/launch-vm/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/launch-vm/</guid><description>Now that everything is installed, let&amp;rsquo;s launch the virtual machine!
Starting the vm This is pretty simple using VirtualBox. Just double click on the vm that we created in the previous step and off you go!
As the virtual machine is getting started there may pop up some warnings like in this image. It is safe to ignore these.
Sign into the vm First you will need to log in. Use these credentials to get started!</description></item><item><title>Activity 1 - Determine User Account</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/activity-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/activity-1/</guid><description>Now we are at the command line. Let&amp;rsquo;s test a simple command to show us the user account.
What are user accounts? Every user in Linux has a user account. These are used to uniquely identify each user.
How do I find out which account I am using? The Linux command whoami will tell you which account you are using. Try it!
In our example above, the terminal output is the name of our user, nuvi.</description></item><item><title>Activity 2 - Determine User Location</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/activity-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/activity-2/</guid><description>So before we can stop the hackers, we need to learn to navigate the Linux filesystem.
Where in the file system are you? The Linux command pwd will display your current location. This stands for Print Working Directory. Try it!
The output above is /home/nuvi and its meaning is explained below:
/: This denotes the root directory, which is the beginning of the Linux file system. home: This denotes the home directory, which is located within the root directory.</description></item><item><title>Answer Key - Linux Basics</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/answerkey/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/answerkey/</guid><description>Activity 1 whoami Activity 2 pwd cd Desktop cd.. Activity 3 ls -l mv Documents/ Downloads/ ls -l Downloads mv Downloads/Documents/ . Activity 4 mkdir files touch file1 vim file1 mv file1 files Activity 5 chmod u=rwx g=rx o=x file1 chmod 751 [insert filename] Activity 6 cd grep -R &amp;quot;Do. Or do not. There is no try.&amp;quot; find . -name *.sh Activity 7 head -n 5 malware.sh tail -n 5 malware.</description></item><item><title>Activity 3 - Explore Current Directory</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/activity-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/activity-3/</guid><description>Now that we know who and where we are, let&amp;rsquo;s take a look around for signs of the hackers.
How do you explore the directory? To see the files in the current directory, we use the ls command. Try ls -l.
The -l flag in the above command tells ls to list long form information.
What information is being displayed? Let&amp;rsquo;s examine the top line of the example above from left to right, for the directory Desktop:</description></item><item><title>Activity 4 - Note Taking Practice</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/activity-4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/activity-4/</guid><description>As a cybersecurity engineer, it is important to take a lot of notes. These are helpful for future reference to understand how the hack happened. Let&amp;rsquo;s step up our workspace!
What if I want to create a new directory? To practice creating a new directory, use the command mkdir in the following format: mkdir new_directory_name.
Lets make a directory called files by typing the command below:
mkdir files As you can see, now when ls -l is run, an additional directory named files appears</description></item><item><title>Activity 5 - Secure User Permissions</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/activity-5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/activity-5/</guid><description>Oh no. Some of our files might have been messed with! Let’s secure our notes, file1. We don&amp;rsquo;t want a hacker to mess with these!
But, How do we know how secure our files are? Is there a command that we have learned so far that can show us how secure our files are?
Feel free to go back if you need to!
We should keep using that command to check if we changed the permissions as expected.</description></item><item><title>Activity 6 - A BAD File</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/activity-6/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/activity-6/</guid><description>I know I had a file secret-message.txt with one of my favorite quotes in it. &amp;ldquo;Do. Or do not. There is no try.&amp;rdquo; Can you help me find it?
Searching for a pattern in a file? grep is a command used to search for a pattern of chars. There are different flags or options that can change how it is used.
The format is: grep [flag] “[pattern]” [filename].
A char is any letter, symbol, or number.</description></item><item><title>Activity 7 - What's wrong with the file?</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/activity-7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/activity-7/</guid><description>Malware can be dangerous! Don&amp;rsquo;t open it right away! Instead let&amp;rsquo;s use the command line to take a peek.
For files that we aren&amp;rsquo;t sure about, we need to peek at them so we don&amp;rsquo;t accidentally open a virus.
How can we look at the first lines of the file? Sometimes you just need to look at the beginning of a file. The command head shows the top of a file.</description></item><item><title>Activity 8 - What's different?</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/activity-8/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/activity-8/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s look at the secret message to make sure this weird malware.sh file hasn&amp;rsquo;t done anything to it!
Differences Do we know a command that can help us find the location of the secret-message.txt file?
Move into that directory and let&amp;rsquo;s check for the quote &amp;ldquo;Do. Or do not. There is no try.&amp;rdquo; from earlier. Do you remember what command can help us check?
This file usually has good and fun quotes, but there seems to be lots of changes.</description></item><item><title>Activity 9 - Remove the Bad File</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/activity-9/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/activity-9/</guid><description>So malware.sh is definitely a bad file left by the hackers. We need to remove it and the directory holding it!
Remove the bad file! rm is a command that removes files.
The format is: rm [filenames].
rm permanently removes the file.
Remove the file we have decided is causing our problems. How can we check that the file was fully removed?
What if we need to remove a directory?</description></item><item><title>Activity 10 - Let's move and replace</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/activity-10/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/activity-10/</guid><description>Great, now that the hackers&amp;rsquo; malicious file won&amp;rsquo;t cause us any more headaches, let&amp;rsquo;s restore the old file so things will run smoothly again.
How to fix the secret-message The command mv can also be used to replace the destination file with the source file.
The format is: mv [source filename] [destination name].
Replace the messed up secret message with the backup that we found earlier.
Let&amp;rsquo;s move the file into the new directory that we made.</description></item><item><title>Activity 11 - Store and protect files</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/activity-11/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/activity-11/</guid><description>Thanks so much for helping us fix my machine! Now let&amp;rsquo;s get everything up into one nice package.
Secure your files, so they don&amp;rsquo;t get tampered with again tar is a command that creates and extracts archived files.
An archive is a collection of archive files. An archive file holds the compressed data of one or more files.
zip is a command that compresses a set of files. The format is: zip [name of zip file] [filenames to be zipped]</description></item><item><title>Closing</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/closing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/closing/</guid><description>Congratulations! You have helped us thwart the hackers evil shenanigans by learning several Linux commands and how to use them. Thanks so much for helping SHH! But don&amp;rsquo;t forget this is all Top Secret!
Click the &amp;ldquo;Download&amp;rdquo; button below to receive your honorary certificate!
Download link</description></item></channel></rss>