<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Workshop Contributor Guidelines on Nuevo Foundation Workshops</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/guidelines/</link><description>Recent content in Workshop Contributor Guidelines on Nuevo Foundation Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 14:08:32 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/guidelines/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Getting Started</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/guidelines/getting-started/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 14:08:32 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/guidelines/getting-started/</guid><description>Getting Started Prerequisites Visual Studio Code Hugo Git and you can get some experience here: https://try.github.io/ Code Contribution to this repository is via the fork model. Contributors push changes to their own &amp;ldquo;forked&amp;rdquo; version of workshops, and then submit a pull request into it requesting those changes be merged.
To get started:
Fork the repo by clicking Fork in the top right corner: From git bash, run (replacing [user-name] with your GitHub user name): \&amp;gt; git clone https://github.</description></item><item><title>How the site is built</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/guidelines/site-architecture/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 14:08:32 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/guidelines/site-architecture/</guid><description>How the site is built The workshops subdomain content is built using the DocDock theme for Hugo. Hugo is a static site generator with a number of benefits:
Content authors can focus on content using markdown and not on the technical implementation of the site or CSS/page styling. Workshops are automagically added to the left table-of-contents and the workshops home page. Hugo works great locally (ex: on an airplane), and Hugo is the fastest static site generator, building the entire workshop site in &amp;lt;2 seconds.</description></item><item><title>Web Developer Guidelines</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/guidelines/web-developer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 14:08:32 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/guidelines/web-developer/</guid><description>This document is for website developers only for changing the Nuevo Foundation workshop project templates and style.
Before getting started Before adding/updating the website, ensure you have synced with the project team and the existing work in the Project Backlog.
Setup Follow the instructions in the Project readme.md to install Git and Hugo to test the project locally.
Web design styles and structure Images: Website images should be themes/images CSS Ignore the SCSS files and just use CSS files in /themes/docdock/static/css/ Make sure to add a reference to the CSS you want to include in the head.</description></item><item><title>Formatting</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/guidelines/formatting/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 14:08:32 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/guidelines/formatting/</guid><description>Formatting Reference Standard Markdown cheatsheet Custom Formatting Options using shortcodes Formatting Examples This theme includes a number of options to customize the look and feel of your site.
Alerts Info {{% alert theme=&amp;quot;info&amp;quot; %}}**This** is an info {{% /alert %}} role=&amp;quot;alert&amp;quot;&amp;gt;This is an info
Success {{% alert theme=&amp;quot;success&amp;quot; %}}**Yeahhh !** is a success{{% /alert %}} role=&amp;quot;alert&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Yeahhh ! is a success
Warning {{% alert theme=&amp;quot;warning&amp;quot; %}}**Be careful** is a warning{{% /alert %}} role=&amp;quot;alert&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Be careful is a warning</description></item></channel></rss>