<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Nuevo Foundation Workshops</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/</link><description>Recent content on Nuevo Foundation Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 12:40:43 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Getting Started</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/android-tictactoe/getting-started/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 14:17:07 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/android-tictactoe/getting-started/</guid><description>What is Android? Android is currently the most used mobile operating system in the world! Android Studio lets you create apps that can be used by these Android devices. In fact, if you have an Android phone, then you can even download the app you&amp;rsquo;re making today onto your phone!
About this Project In this project we&amp;rsquo;ve given you a mostly working Android application that&amp;rsquo;s a game of Tic-Tac-Toe. It needs your help to fix some problems and add a few parts to make it a great game!</description></item><item><title>Using Virtual Machines Part 1</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/vbox-setup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/vbox-setup/</guid><description>So you can help us, we are providing you with a copy of the hacked computer as a virtual machine.
What is a virtual machine A virtual machine (commonly called a vm) is a computer file (called an image), that behaves like an actual computer.
In other words, creating a computer within a computer. It runs in a window, much like any other program.
This gives you the same experience on a vm as you would on a regular computer.</description></item><item><title>Welcome to your new Summer job!</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-tensorflow/welcome/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 16:19:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-tensorflow/welcome/</guid><description>Hey there, congratulations! You have been hired at a appearel returns processing warehouse for the summer!
Your job is to take returns of clothing and sort them based on the type of clothing they are. At orientation, your supervisor shows you the traditional, by-hand method to sorting this clothing. On your first day, you notice it is more time consuming than you expected. Not wanting to do more work than you have to of course, you convice your superviors that you can devise a more efficent method using machine learning.</description></item><item><title>Starting Up</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/phaser-space-invaders-game/starting-up/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/phaser-space-invaders-game/starting-up/</guid><description>Starting Up To begin, open your preferred internet browser (such as Edge, Firefox, Google Chrome, Internet Explorer), and go to https://repl.it/@nuevofoundation/Phaser-Space-Invaders. Your screen should look like this:
For now, we will ignore the content of the project (the code), and we will instead go over the basics of how to use the website. On the left hand of the screen, you will see a list of files that contain code, or instructions for the computer to run.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/guidelines/getting-started/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 14:08:32 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/guidelines/getting-started/</guid><description>Getting Started Prerequisites Visual Studio Code Hugo Git and you can get some experience here: https://try.github.io/ Code Contribution to this repository is via the fork model. Contributors push changes to their own &amp;ldquo;forked&amp;rdquo; version of workshops, and then submit a pull request into it requesting those changes be merged.
To get started:
Fork the repo by clicking Fork in the top right corner: From git bash, run (replacing [user-name] with your GitHub user name): \&amp;gt; git clone https://github.</description></item><item><title>Starting up with Repl.it</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/jsappybird/repl-it/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/jsappybird/repl-it/</guid><description>Today you will be using Repl.it to build JSappy bird. Here is an example interactive window that you will use today:
Open your favorite internet browser (such as Edge, Firefox, Google Chrome, Internet Explorer) and go to https://repl.it.
You should see something like the following screen:
Here is the final output of the game:
https://jsappybird-answers--nuevofoundation.repl.co/</description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/javascript-basics/introduction/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/javascript-basics/introduction/</guid><description>JavaScript Basics Hi there! If you&amp;rsquo;re reading this, it hopefully means that you&amp;rsquo;re here to learn JavaScript 😁🥳. Whether this is your first time coding or you want a way to quickly pick up a new language - you&amp;rsquo;re in the right place! Get ready to discover the power of programming and have fun.
What is Code? We can&amp;rsquo;t learn how to code without first understanding what exactly code is. Think of your favorite website, if you can&amp;rsquo;t think of one let&amp;rsquo;s take NuevoFoundation.</description></item><item><title>Activity 1: Create a color board</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-pixel/activities/activity-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-pixel/activities/activity-1/</guid><description>Example for basic colorboard Here is an example of how to make a color board with the color red, a width of 60, and a length of 30.
#This is the example for creating a colorboard. from PIL import Image img = Image.new(&amp;#39;RGB&amp;#39;, (60, 30), &amp;#39;red&amp;#39;) img.save(&amp;#39;pil_red.png&amp;#39;) Create your own colorboard! Choose your favorite color and make a color board to play with! Here are some example colors you can choose from, but you can also pick your own color.</description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-tictactoe/using-repl-it/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-tictactoe/using-repl-it/</guid><description>Tic Tac Toe Summary Using Repl.it Today you will be using Repl.it to code in Java. Here is the starter code you will use today:
Before we start, let&amp;rsquo;s first understand how the window works. The Main.java file contains code, or instructions for the computer to run. By pressing the run button, you tell the computer to perform the instructions in the code. Any results from running the code will be displayed on the bottom white screen, under the result tab.</description></item><item><title>Using Repl.It</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-basics/activity-0/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-basics/activity-0/</guid><description>Using Repl.it Today you will be using Repl.it to learn how to code in Java. Here is an example interactive window that you will use today:
Before we start, let&amp;rsquo;s first understand how the window works. The Main.java file contains code, or instructions for the computer to run. By pressing the run button, you tell the computer to perform the instructions in the code. Any results from running the code will be displayed on the bottom white screen, under the result tab.</description></item><item><title>Import an image module</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-pixel/colors_and_pixels/load_image_module/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-pixel/colors_and_pixels/load_image_module/</guid><description>Setting up the project To get started let’s start with importing a module. What does that mean? To do fun stuff with images, we need to unlock some functions to use. To get these functions we need to import a module. In this case if we import the module Pillow, we can use some functions that will help us modify images.
Firstly, let’s delete everything in the main.py file. Then, add the following statements:</description></item><item><title>More about functions</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/functions/more-about-functions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/functions/more-about-functions/</guid><description>Suppose you have many lines of code, and you would like to give this section of code a meaningful name. Functions are blocks of code that do just that. A function is a set of instructions that we give to the computer to store, and it can take in parameters (input data) and output data. A function in Python looks like this:
Let’s analyze this piece of code. The def tells the computer that you are writing a function.</description></item><item><title>Strings</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/data-types/strings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/data-types/strings/</guid><description>Anything that is surrounded by quotation marks is called a string. This is how a computer represents words or sentences. For example, &amp;ldquo;a&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;2&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;banana!&amp;quot;, and &amp;ldquo;Hello World&amp;rdquo; are strings, but 2 and Hello World are not strings, because the quotation marks are missing. You can combine many strings together using the + sign!
The strings that you combine do not have to be real words! For example, &amp;quot;Ap&amp;quot; + &amp;quot;ple&amp;quot; will produce the string &amp;quot;Apple&amp;quot;.</description></item><item><title>Using Repl.It</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/pygame-pong/using-repl-it/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/pygame-pong/using-repl-it/</guid><description>To build our game, we will use the Pygame library, which provides a set of readymade functionality that we can use to build Pong and its animations.
Using Repl.it Today, you will be using Repl.it to build the Pong game.
If you would like a re-cap on how to use Repl.it, check out the following Python basics tutorial
Next, let&amp;rsquo;s explain further some of the code that has been provided to you in the main.</description></item><item><title>Using Repl.It</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-turtle/using-repl-it/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-turtle/using-repl-it/</guid><description>To help Alex live in a beehive, he needs to learn how to create a honeycomb! We will use Python&amp;rsquo;s turtle library to draw a honeycomb for Alex.
Using Repl.it Today you will be using Repl.it to learn how to code in Python. Here is an example interactive window that you will use today:
Before we start, let&amp;rsquo;s first understand how the window works. The main.py file contains code, or instructions for the computer to run.</description></item><item><title>What is a micro:bit?</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/microbit-distance-checker/what-is-microbit/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/microbit-distance-checker/what-is-microbit/</guid><description>What is a micro:bit? A micro:bit is a programmable mini computer! It can be coded from any web browser in various languages like javaScript, Python, Scratch, and Blocks. For our session today, we will be using MakeCode Blocks.
Your micro:bit has the following physical features:
25 individually-programmable LEDs 2 programmable buttons Physical connection pins Motion sensors (accelerometer and compass) Wireless communication via bluetooth radio USB interface If you want to learn more about each individual component and all the features that come with your micro:bit, you can click here.</description></item><item><title>Conditional statements</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/conditional-statements-loops/conditional-statements/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/conditional-statements-loops/conditional-statements/</guid><description>Now that we know the basics of print statements, variables, and reading in input from the user – we can combine all these awesome skills with conditional statements. Conditional statements allow the computer to make decisions based off the value of an expression. In the real world, we use conditional statements all the time to make decisions! For example, if it is raining outside, then I use an umbrella. In this example, the I evaluated the weather outside and because it was raining, I made the sequential decision to use an umbrella.</description></item><item><title>Meet DJ Nuevo</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-earsketch/meet-dj-nuevo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-earsketch/meet-dj-nuevo/</guid><description>Nuevo has new headphones! Can you find yours? You got contacted to make Nuvi&amp;rsquo;s next hit mixtape, but when you get to the studio, Nuvi says their next project is going to be produced all in code. This is something that hasn&amp;rsquo;t been done before, are you up to the challenge? Look around yourself to find your headphones and get ready to join him!
Before we start, make sure that your headphones are working.</description></item><item><title>Starting Up</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/csharp-guess-the-word/starting-up/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/csharp-guess-the-word/starting-up/</guid><description>Starting Up The goal of today&amp;rsquo;s activity is to learn C# skills and incorporate your new-found knowledge to create a Guess The Word game! Let&amp;rsquo;s get the game set up.
Open your favorite internet browser (such as Edge, Firefox, Google Chrome, Internet Explorer), and go to https://aka.ms/nuevoguesstheword. Your screen should look like this:
We will ignore some of the details on this screen, but we will go over some of the basics that show up.</description></item><item><title>Starting up with Repl.it</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/basics/repl-it/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/basics/repl-it/</guid><description>Open your favorite internet browser (such as Edge, Firefox, Google Chrome, Internet Explorer) and go to https://repl.it. Scroll to the bottom of the page, look for languages, search for Python and click it.
You should see something like the following screen:
We will ignore some of the details on this screen, but we will go over some of the basics that show up. The main.py file contains code, or instructions for the computer to run.</description></item><item><title>Time to Create</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/adventure/time-to-create/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/adventure/time-to-create/</guid><description>It’s time to start creating our own stories with all the skills we’ve learned today! The question that we are tackling today is how to get the audience involved with the story line, and the answer to this is CODE!</description></item><item><title>Bob goes fishing</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security-phishing/bob-goes-fishing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security-phishing/bob-goes-fishing/</guid><description>Meet our friend Bob. Bob is a nice and jolly gentleman. His hobbies are travelling and fishing. One fine evening Bob received an email saying he won a free trip to the &amp;ldquo;Bahamas&amp;rdquo;. Bob got excited. He immediately clicked the link to enter his personal details and waited for his itinerary to come.
Bob decided to go shopping for his trip. He bought new clothes and a new fishing rod. However, 24 hours later, he still didn&amp;rsquo;t receive a confirmation for his trip.</description></item><item><title>Generate a random number</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-guess-number/generate-random-number/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-guess-number/generate-random-number/</guid><description>Python includes a library called random that helps you generate random numbers. You can use this in your program by writing import random at the top of your program and using the randint function to generate a number between a range.
This would generate a random number between 1 and 10
random.randint(1,10) Try running the below code a few times to see what you get!
You can also play around by changing the range of random numbers.</description></item><item><title>Lists</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/data-structures/lists/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/data-structures/lists/</guid><description>Lists are the ordered collection of items and can be written as comma separated values inside square bracket []. You can access the element of a list by using indexes inside square bracket. The index starts from 0 and goes up to the (number of elements in the list - 1) and the first element is at index 0. So, a list having 6 elements will have indices from 0 to 5.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Alice, Bob and Eve</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security/meeting-alice-bob-eve/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security/meeting-alice-bob-eve/</guid><description>Meet our friend Bob. Bob has a secret that he doesn’t want to share, he would like to keep it secured. He has the secret locked somewhere safe. Only Bob has the key to the lock to make sure that no one can get to his secret but him.
Meet our not so good friend Eve. Eve wants access to Bob’s secret.
Eve realizes that to get to Bob&amp;lsquo;s secret, they need to first get past Bob&amp;lsquo;s lock.</description></item><item><title>Setting up the PC</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/arduino/setting-up-the-pc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/arduino/setting-up-the-pc/</guid><description>Getting to know the Arduino IDE Download and install the Arduino IDE from:
the Microsoft Store (quicker install) - https://www.microsoft.com/store/productId/9NBLGGH4RSD8 or from the Arduino website https://www.arduino.cc/en/Main/Software (pick the latest version) Once the software has been installed on your computer, go ahead and open it up. This is the Arduino IDE and is the place where all the programming will happen. Take some time to look around and get comfortable with it.</description></item><item><title>The Components</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/adafruit/the-components/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/adafruit/the-components/</guid><description>The components we will use for the project are listed below. Make sure you have all of these before starting:
One Adafruit USB-C to USB cord 2 alligator clip wires, any colors Two oranges</description></item><item><title>Android Setup</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/android-tictactoe/android-setup/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 14:17:07 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/android-tictactoe/android-setup/</guid><description>Follow the steps below to get Android Studio installed on your computer. If you already have Android Studio installed, open it up and skip to the next step!
These steps have examples for installing on Windows computers. However, the steps are similar for other types of computers as well.
Download and Install Android Studio Download Android Studio for your operating system. Follow these steps to install Android Studio. Set the JAVA_HOME environment variable Android Studio comes with a version of Java needed for certain parts of the application to run.</description></item><item><title>Using Virtual Machines Part 2</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/vm-import-setup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/vm-import-setup/</guid><description>Good work on getting the host environment ready! Now let&amp;rsquo;s load the image of the hacked computer as a vm.
What is an image Images come in a variety of types. We have photographs, which are images. The images in computers are very similar. Both are copies of things from a single point in time.
This means what we will be working with is a copy of the computer that has been acting weird.</description></item><item><title>Activity 1 - Importing the Tensorflow library and datasets</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-tensorflow/activity-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 16:19:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-tensorflow/activity-1/</guid><description>The first thing we have to do is to import the tensorflow library in order to use functions that will allow us to train your model.
We will also be implementing plots to visualize the prediction of our model, so for that we need to import the following libraries:
# Importing TensorFlow and tf.keras libraries import tensorflow as tf from tensorflow import keras # Helper libraries for statistics and plotting import numpy as np import matplotlib.</description></item><item><title>The Game's File Structure</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/phaser-space-invaders-game/game-structure/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/phaser-space-invaders-game/game-structure/</guid><description>As you can see, we&amp;rsquo;ve already created many files for you. The structure of the game has already been laid out, and you will be filling each file with content. So, in order to begin, we must first have at least a basic understanding of what each file does and how they relate to each other.
Firstly, phaser.min.js is simply a JavaScript file that contains code that allows the game to run Phaser, the framework we are using to make the game.</description></item><item><title>1. Set Up the Board!</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-tictactoe/activity-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-tictactoe/activity-1/</guid><description>Prerequisites (from Java: Basics) activity-1: Print Statements and Comments activity-2: Variables and Types activity-3: Operators activity-5: Methods activity-6: Object and Classes activity-7: Data Structures (Array &amp;amp; ArrayList) These are the concepts from the Java: Basics workshop that we will use in this activity. Please refer to these activity to review or learn the concepts before continuing!
In this activity, we will have a program that prints out the game board and gaming prompt, like the output below:</description></item><item><title>Activity 2: Modify your color board</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-pixel/activities/activity-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-pixel/activities/activity-2/</guid><description>Example one: Make a diagonal #This creates the original colorboard. from PIL import Image img = Image.new(&amp;#39;RGB&amp;#39;, (60, 30), &amp;#39;red&amp;#39;) img.save(&amp;#39;pil_red.png&amp;#39;) #This uses a nested while loop to change the picture. x = 0 y = 0 while x &amp;lt; 10: while y &amp;lt; 20: img.putpixel( (x,y), (0, 0, 0)) x += 1 y += 1 img.save(&amp;#39;pil_red.png&amp;#39;) This is the picture before changing. This is the picture after changing. Example two: Make a rectangle.</description></item><item><title>Print Statements and Comments</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-basics/activity-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-basics/activity-1/</guid><description>1. Let the Program Speak! Let’s try to write a program that says Hello World out by typing the line of code System.out.print(&amp;quot;Hello World&amp;quot;);
The program prints out whatever you typed in the parenthesis of System.out.print(. And, each line of code ends with ;.
After, add more statements to print numbers by putting numbers in the parenthesis (i.e. System.out.print(2020)) or a symbol by putting one symbol between 2 single quotes ' (i.</description></item><item><title>Built in Functions</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/functions/built-in/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/functions/built-in/</guid><description>There are many built-in functions in python that can be used to increase the ease of writing code. Let&amp;rsquo;s discuss a few of them here.
sort() This function is used to sort the values in data structures such as arrays and lists.
arr = [8,5,1,4,6] arr.sort() print(&amp;#39;The sorted arr is :&amp;#39;,arr) #prints The sorted arr is [1,4,5,6,8] find() Returns the first occurence of the input(pattern) to the find() provided in the given string.</description></item><item><title>Numbers</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/data-types/numbers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/data-types/numbers/</guid><description>The computer can also do your regular math that you do in school. Use print to print out the result from the math expressions. No quotation marks are needed for numbers! Unlike strings, you can do math on numbers.
The computer does division differently from your regular calculator. Computer division will exclude remainders or decimals.
For example,
15/4 makes 3 and not 3.75
You can also try using the math symbols to make your own expressions!</description></item><item><title>Open an image</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-pixel/colors_and_pixels/open-image/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-pixel/colors_and_pixels/open-image/</guid><description>To change an image, we must open an image. We can use the Pillow Image module we just imported in the setup. Let’s first find some images to open. Find an image of your choice and download it. Once you have downloaded it, navigate back to your repl.it window and upload your image by clicking on the three dots and selecting ‘upload file’.
For example, to upload the cat.jpg file:</description></item><item><title>Writing to Console (Print statement)</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/basics/writing-to-console/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/basics/writing-to-console/</guid><description>Make your program talk to you! Print statements are used to print something on the console. Use print(&amp;quot;Hello World&amp;quot;) to print Hello World in the output screen. We will later learn that print is a function and we use it to perform a print job. Whatever you pass to the print function is printed on the screen. Let&amp;rsquo;s start by doing a print statement. A print statement allows you to take control of the computer and make it print something out!</description></item><item><title>Basics</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/web-basics/basics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 17:53:41 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/web-basics/basics/</guid><description>What is a website? A website is just a page that can be found on the Internet. It is displayed through a browser when you type the address (aka unique name) in the address bar.
Parts of a website Common website elements include navigation bars, footers, search bars, and contact forms.
Website design The first step in making a website is to decide which elements we want, and how they will look.</description></item><item><title>The Basics - Class and Object</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/pygame-pong/the-basics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/pygame-pong/the-basics/</guid><description>Classes and objects Before you start building a game, you should know how to draw different objects and modify them as per the way they need to look and move on computer screen.
In order to build objects, you first decide how they should look, what role they should perform in your game, and how player can control their movement on screen. You do this by creating a class for each object you want on screen.</description></item><item><title>Broadcasting a Signal</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/microbit-distance-checker/broadcasting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/microbit-distance-checker/broadcasting/</guid><description>Turning On the Radio Today we&amp;rsquo;ll be using the Bluetooth radio on your micro:bit to figure out how far away you are from other micro:bits. The first thing we need to do is turn on the radio and tune it to a channel. Click on the section that says Radio. It&amp;rsquo;s the pink section which is fifth from the top. Choose &amp;ldquo;radio set group 1&amp;rdquo; and drag it into the blue &amp;ldquo;on start&amp;rdquo; block in the workspace.</description></item><item><title>The Basics - Drawing a colored line</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-turtle/the-basics/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-turtle/the-basics/</guid><description>Before Alex can learn how to create a beehive, he must first learn how to draw a colored line. We will add code to the below repl.it window, and we will do this in two parts.
First, we need tell the turtle what color we want the line to be. To do this, let&amp;rsquo;s type in:
turtle.color(&amp;quot;orange&amp;quot;) Let&amp;rsquo;s try to understand this line of code in more detail.</description></item><item><title>Music Basics</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-earsketch/music-basics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-earsketch/music-basics/</guid><description>Basics first. A few things about music. What is Music? Music is the chronological organisation of sounds; that is, making certain sounds at certain times, which make melodic, rhythmic and harmonic sense. The first, most basic concept, is keeping the sounds &amp;ldquo;in time&amp;rdquo;. This leads us to some of the first few musical concepts: beat, rhythm, duration &amp;amp; tempo.
Beat is the regular pulse which provides a timeline for the rhythm to anchor itself to.</description></item><item><title>Section 1: Story Boarding</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/adventure/story-boarding/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/adventure/story-boarding/</guid><description>To get started, pull out a piece a paper and start &amp;ldquo;story boarding&amp;rdquo;. What does that mean? In order to develop a great story that allows the reader to choose between options, one can outline the flow of their story. This is a great planning step, that will you help you tremendously once you start coding! I would start with the 3 or 4 main choices your protagonist is going to make in the story.</description></item><item><title>Writing to Console</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/csharp-guess-the-word/writing-to-console/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/csharp-guess-the-word/writing-to-console/</guid><description>Writing to Console Console.WriteLine means to tell the computer to print the sentence enclosed within the parentheses () out onto the console.
Working Together In the repl.it window below, press run. You see that Hello World is printed out to the screen on the right. Without removing the quotation marks, try changing &amp;quot;Hello World&amp;quot; to another sentence. Press run to see if anything changes. Add another Console.WriteLine below the current line to print a second sentence below the first sentence.</description></item><item><title>Building the DJ station</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/adafruit/building-the-dj-station/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/adafruit/building-the-dj-station/</guid><description>Hooking up the oranges Grab an orange and one of your wires. Open up one of the alligator clips and insert the bottom half into the orange, leaving the top part of the clip on the outside. This is easiest to do if you insert it in the middle of the bottom of the orange. The same spot where you’d start peeling if you were going to eat the orange.</description></item><item><title>Create the game</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-guess-number/create-game/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-guess-number/create-game/</guid><description>Accept user input This game will use some of the concepts you learned in the Python Basics section. You will need to know how to use the following concepts. If you are not familiar with any of these, please go back to review them.
While loops Writing to console Reading from the console Conditional statements Random numbers You will need to code this game so that it randomly generates a number.</description></item><item><title>Else-if Condition</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/conditional-statements-loops/else-if-statement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/conditional-statements-loops/else-if-statement/</guid><description>We have already learned some basic if-else conditions from previous workshops, click on the link below if you want to review.
Conditional statements We will introduce a new condition called &amp;ldquo;elif&amp;rdquo;.
Elif Condition Elif Keyword represents the &amp;ldquo;else-if&amp;rdquo; condition. It is used when you want to have if the last if condition is not true, try this condition.
# This is my first line of code if expression: statement(s) elif expression: statement(s) else: statement(s) Let&amp;rsquo;s see an example # This is an example if 1 &amp;gt; 3: print(&amp;#39;1&amp;gt;3&amp;#39;) elif 1 == 3: print(&amp;#39;1=3&amp;#39;) else: print(&amp;#39;1&amp;lt;3&amp;#39;) Since we can see that 1 greater than 3 is false, so it evaluates to false.</description></item><item><title>Loops</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/conditional-statements-loops/loops/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/conditional-statements-loops/loops/</guid><description>Loops in Python If you want to repeat a task multiple times, Python has a way to do that easily using loops. There are two types of basic loops in python: for loops and while loops.
For loops For loops iterate over a sequence. Let&amp;rsquo;s say you wanted to repeat a simple task 5 times. Here is how you would do it.
The following for loop iterates through each of the numbers in the list [1,2,3,4,5], and assigns the value x to it.</description></item><item><title>Password Basics</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security/password-basics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security/password-basics/</guid><description>Our Secret Agent Alice solves the case by explaining Bob about Passwords!!!
What is a Password? Passwords are the key to the lock to your virtual world. Just like your secret is kept safe in a secure room using a lock and a key similarly your personal information on the internet is secured by your login password and username. The secure room is only as secure as the key to the lock on the door.</description></item><item><title>Phishing Basics</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security-phishing/phishing-basics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security-phishing/phishing-basics/</guid><description>Our Secret Agent Alice explains to Bob about Phishing!!!
What is Phishing? Just like when fishing, one uses a bait to catch fish on a rod, malicious hackers use different types of bait to steal personal information from unsuspecting people.
Phishing is a type of social engineering attack which is used to steal sensitive data, including login credentials, banking and credit card details. It occurs when a Hacker, posing as a trusted entity, lures an individual using email, text message, or phone.</description></item><item><title>The Components</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/arduino/the-components/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/arduino/the-components/</guid><description>The Components The components we will use for the project are shown below. Make sure you have all these components before starting:
Elegoo UNO Project Super Starter Kit with Tutorial for Arduino includes all hardware (with exception to the computer)
Core components needed for all activities Arduino UNO R3 USB A to B cable Windows 10 PC Arduino IDE software (download) Additional components needed for specific activities (5) LEDs (any color) (5) 220ohm resistor https://somanytech.</description></item><item><title>Tuples</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/data-structures/tuples/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/data-structures/tuples/</guid><description>A Tuple is also an ordered collection of elements just like lists, but tuples are immutable. So you can not change the elements of a tuple after it is assigned (unlike lists where you are allowed to do so). This immutable nature makes tuples very useful when you don&amp;rsquo;t want your data to be mutated through out the program. Along with this, tuples are generally used to store elements of different data types.</description></item><item><title>Puzzle 1</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/android-tictactoe/puzzle1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 14:17:07 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/android-tictactoe/puzzle1/</guid><description>Run the Game Press the play button button (►) at the top of Android Studio to start the game. You&amp;rsquo;ll see that the title at the top of the app says Toe-Tac-Tic (that doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem right!); let&amp;rsquo;s change it to Tic-Tac-Toe.
Solve the Puzzle Double-click the strings.xml file under app → res → values: How can you modify this file to say Tic-Tac-Toe?</description></item><item><title>Starting up the Virtual Machine</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/launch-vm/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/launch-vm/</guid><description>Now that everything is installed, let&amp;rsquo;s launch the virtual machine!
Starting the vm This is pretty simple using VirtualBox. Just double click on the vm that we created in the previous step and off you go! As the virtual machine is getting started there may pop up some warnings like in this image.
It is safe to ignore these.
Sign into the vm First you will need to log in.</description></item><item><title>Activity 2 - Displaying RGB Color values for images</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-tensorflow/activity-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 16:19:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-tensorflow/activity-2/</guid><description>You now take a picture of your shoe from your samples.
Go ahead and copy and paste the following code into your Google Colab notebook:
plt.figure() plt.imshow(train_images[0]) #Shows the first image in the data set as a plot or different colored pixels plt.colorbar() #displays the color bar on the right plt.grid(False) plt.show() #displays the entire plot Question 1 Change the index of the “train_images[x]” and look at the color bar on the right, what is the max pixel value?</description></item><item><title>Activity 3: Challenge: Design new elements</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-pixel/activities/activity-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-pixel/activities/activity-3/</guid><description>Using loops, you can actually design your own elements on the colorboard. You can design your own logo or anything you want on this color board. Here is an example we provided for you.
Example: make an N. #This creates the original colorboard. from PIL import Image img = Image.new(&amp;#39;RGB&amp;#39;, (60, 30), &amp;#39;white&amp;#39;) #This uses nested while loop to change the colorboard. #Left vertical line for x in range(10, 15): for y in range(5, 25): img.</description></item><item><title>Phaser Fundamentals</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/phaser-space-invaders-game/phaser-fundementals/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/phaser-space-invaders-game/phaser-fundementals/</guid><description>Part 1: The Config Variable Let&amp;rsquo;s go over some of the fundamentals of Phaser, a game framework that uses HTML and JavaScript to create games for the web! This is what you&amp;rsquo;ll be learning to use in this workshop.
Go to game.js. Every Phaser game will start out off with a variable that stores the configurations for the game (often named config like we have here).
var config = { type: Phaser.</description></item><item><title>How the site is built</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/guidelines/site-architecture/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 14:08:32 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/guidelines/site-architecture/</guid><description>How the site is built The workshops subdomain content is built using the DocDock theme for Hugo. Hugo is a static site generator with a number of benefits:
Content authors can focus on content using markdown and not on the technical implementation of the site or CSS/page styling. Workshops are automagically added to the left table-of-contents and the workshops home page. Hugo works great locally (ex: on an airplane), and Hugo is the fastest static site generator, building the entire workshop site in &amp;lt;2 seconds.</description></item><item><title>2. Read and Process Input</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-tictactoe/activity-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-tictactoe/activity-2/</guid><description>Prerequisites (from Java: Basics) activity-1: Print Statements and Comments activity-2: Variables and Types activity-3: Operators activity-4: Control Structures activity-5: Methods activity-6: Object and Classes These are the concepts from the Java: Basics workshop that we will use in this activity. Please refer to these activity to review or learn the concepts before continuing!
1. Importing Packages In Java, an efficient way to obtain user input is to use the Scanner class in java.</description></item><item><title>Variables and Types</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-basics/activity-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-basics/activity-2/</guid><description>1. Variables: Name It! In the last exercise, we learn to print different statements with System.out.print().
While it&amp;rsquo;s great to print out a number or a sentence, we haven&amp;rsquo;t given them a meaning.
In Java, we introduce the idea of a variable for data. A variable is like a box that stores a piece of data with a name.
For example, there can be a variable called myName that stored &amp;quot;Patrick&amp;quot;, another variable called loveMusic that stored true, and another variable called age that stored 3.</description></item><item><title>Booleans</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/data-types/booleans/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/data-types/booleans/</guid><description>Booleans are True or False statements. Unlike strings or numbers, booleans store statements of truth: is what I&amp;rsquo;m saying true or false?
For example, if I say, &amp;ldquo;You are a robot&amp;rdquo;, a boolean can store whether this statement is true. In this case, since you are not a robot (hopefully!), False would be stored.
What are the boolean answers to these questions about you?
I am a human. _______ I have 25 fingers.</description></item><item><title>Starting up</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/jsappybird/steps-to-start/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/jsappybird/steps-to-start/</guid><description>Open the Activity-1 Scaffold URL to do the activity. https://repl.it/@nuevofoundation/JSappyBird-Activity-1-Scaffold
When you make changes to the scaffold you will be created as anonymous users.
You should see something like the following screen:</description></item><item><title>Putting it together</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/web-basics/putting-together/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 17:53:41 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/web-basics/putting-together/</guid><description>Putting it together For your browser to understand what each element of your site is, we need to label them with HTML tags. HTML stands for Hypertext Markup Language. Tags are words surrounded by the symbols &amp;lt;and&amp;gt;. For example, the &amp;lt;img&amp;gt; tag tells your browser “this is an image.” The &amp;lt;button&amp;gt; tag tells it “this is a button.”
Tags can also be used to organize your webpage! The image below outlines the structure of a basic webpage.</description></item><item><title>Activity 1 - Define the width of the Pong screen</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/pygame-pong/activity-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/pygame-pong/activity-1/</guid><description>Activity 1 You can adjust the boundary of the Pong game by adjusting the height and width of the rectangle that represents the boundary.
Go to the code containing the Pong game. Press run. Notice that the game&amp;rsquo;s boundary doesn&amp;rsquo;t look right - see the image below. Let&amp;rsquo;s fix this in this activity, so the game boundary looks good.
Find // TODO (ACTIVITY 1) in the code. Modify the WIDTH attribute of Pong class.</description></item><item><title>Built-in Math Functions</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/functions/built-in-math/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/functions/built-in-math/</guid><description>Python provides a number of important built-in functions that we can use without needing to provide the function definition. In this section, we will learn about some of the built-in math functions using that you can perform mathematical tasks on numbers.
The max() and min() functions give us the largest and smallest values in a list, respectively:
x = min(20, 10, 50, 25) #x = 10 print(x) y = max(20, 10, 50, 25) #y = 50 print(y) The abs() function give us the absolute(positive) value of number:</description></item><item><title>Activity 1 - Drawing a square</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-turtle/activity-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-turtle/activity-1/</guid><description>Kudos! You helped Alex draw a line! Now let’s step it up and help Alex draw a square. To draw a square, we need to follow these steps:
Go forward for 50 steps Turn left by 90 degrees Go forward for 50 steps Turn left by 90 degrees Go forward for 50 steps Turn left by 90 degrees Go forward for 50 steps Remember to use turtle.forward() to draw lines.</description></item><item><title>Receiving a Message</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/microbit-distance-checker/receiving/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/microbit-distance-checker/receiving/</guid><description>Now that we&amp;rsquo;re sending messages and listening for them, we need to use that information to find out how close together or far apart our micro:bits are. To do that, we need to know how strong the signal we&amp;rsquo;re receiving is. Go back into the Radio section and this time drag the &amp;ldquo;on radio received (receivedNumber)&amp;rdquo; block and drag it to an empty spot on your workspace. It should not be inside of any other block.</description></item><item><title>Comments</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/csharp-guess-the-word/comments/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/csharp-guess-the-word/comments/</guid><description>Comments Developers often need to collaborate with other developers. Comments are an easy way for developers to write notes in the code and communicate with others. Comments are ignored by the computer; thus, they are also an easy way to tell the computer to not run certain lines of code. There are two ways to create comments:
To comment out one line, place // in front of a line of code.</description></item><item><title>Section 2: Transferring the Story Board to Code!</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/adventure/story-board-code/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/adventure/story-board-code/</guid><description>It’s time to open repl.it. Now it is time to create, let’s get creative!
You can continue working off Nuvi’s story line:
You can work on a template for a Choose Your Own Adventure game:
Or you can start from scratch and make it your own! Just go to repl.it and start story telling!</description></item><item><title>A closer look</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security-phishing/a-closer-look/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security-phishing/a-closer-look/</guid><description>Bob received the following email the other night.
What do you think is suspicious here? Let&amp;rsquo;s analyze the email: The sender's email address is suspicious and you don't know this email sender personally.
Lucrative offer in the subject line suggests it's too good to be true.
You received an email during irregular business hours.
These words show a sense of urgency.
The sender is asking you to click on a link or open an attachment that you don't know about.</description></item><item><title>Activity</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security/activity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security/activity/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s play a game!
Write your favorite sentence in the text box below. Make sure it has at least five words. (E.g. I like playing volleyball at the beach.) Now take the first letter of each word from the above sentence and write inside the text box. (E.g. ilpvatb) Add some numbers to the text. Remember the position of the numbers. (E.g. 1ilpvatb6) Finally, let's add some special characters to the text.</description></item><item><title>Basics of colors</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-pixel/colors_and_pixels/basic-of-colors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-pixel/colors_and_pixels/basic-of-colors/</guid><description>Basics of Colors While going through all kinds of pictures online, have you ever questioned how those pictures get their colors? Actually, computers have RGB mode to represent colors.
RGB format In Python, we follow a specific format when defining colors: (R, G, B), where &amp;ldquo;R&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;G&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;B&amp;rdquo; are all integers. &amp;ldquo;R&amp;rdquo; represents some amount of red, &amp;ldquo;G&amp;rdquo; represents some amount of green, and &amp;ldquo;B&amp;rdquo; represents some amount of blue.</description></item><item><title>Circuit Basics</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/arduino/circuit-basics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/arduino/circuit-basics/</guid><description>The components, in detail Imagine our circuit is a play. Before the final performance in front of an audience, we need a place to practice. This is where the breadboard comes in.
Breadboards are simple platforms that we can use to build temporary circuits for testing and debugging before finalizing our design and permanently soldering (welding) it together. Breadboards allow us to easily add, remove, or reposition components. Below on the left is an image of a breadboard.</description></item><item><title>Comments</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/basics/comments/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/basics/comments/</guid><description>Make notes while you are coding Comments are the parts of the code that do not get evaluated. In Python, they are preceded by the # symbol. Anything after the # symbol is part of the comment and is ignored by your code. Comments are put in the code to tell the readers what the code is doing. They can make maintenance of code easy and can also help in finding bugs.</description></item><item><title>Creating the Program</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/adafruit/creating-the-program/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/adafruit/creating-the-program/</guid><description>Open your favorite internet browser (such as Edge, Firefox, Google Chrome, Internet Explorer), and go to https://aka.ms/oranges. Your screen should look like this:
Defining the Variables Today we are going to be using oranges to tell our Adafruit when to make noise. The first thing we need to do is give the computer a name for each orange and where to look for what they are saying. We do the first part by defining a variable.</description></item><item><title>Python Basics</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-earsketch/python-basics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-earsketch/python-basics/</guid><description>Python basics To code music, we need to learn a little Python. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, it won&amp;rsquo;t bite you. Python is one of the languages that we humans use to tell computers what to do. These languages are known as &amp;ldquo;programming languages&amp;rdquo;. We will learn Python concepts throughout the class, but let&amp;rsquo;s start with a simple print statement.
If you want to jump to a specific Python section, click on the topic below:</description></item><item><title>Sets</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/data-structures/sets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/data-structures/sets/</guid><description>Just like a list, a set is a collection of items. The difference between a set and a list is that a set cannot contain duplicates. So, if you have 5 chocolates and you put them in a set, you&amp;rsquo;ll only be left with 1 chocolate as duplicates will be removed. 😢
In the image above, the left side represents Indoor Games (Chess &amp;amp; Table Tennis) while the right side represents the Outdoor Games (Cricket &amp;amp; Football).</description></item><item><title>Game Application Structure</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/android-tictactoe/app-structure/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 14:17:07 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/android-tictactoe/app-structure/</guid><description>Back to Foundations Now that the game has the right title, let&amp;rsquo;s dive deeper into all these files in the game folder. What do they all mean? How does it contribute to the game? AndroidManifest.xml Every project in Android includes a manifest file. For your game, this is the AndroidManifest.xml file. The manifest file defines the metadata for your game, for instance, it can define the icon and the overall theme for your game application.</description></item><item><title>Activity 1 - Determine User Account</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/activity-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/activity-1/</guid><description>Now we are at the command line. Let&amp;rsquo;s test a simple command to show us the user account.
What are user accounts? Every user in Linux has a user account. These are used to uniquely identify each user.
How do I find out which account I am using? The Linux command whoami will tell you which account you are using.
Try it:
whoami In our example above, the terminal output is the name of our user, nuvi.</description></item><item><title>Progress Update 1</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-tensorflow/progress_update_1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 16:19:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-tensorflow/progress_update_1/</guid><description>If you would like to test the following code, visit this link
To edit this code, click on the &amp;lsquo;Copy to Drive&amp;rsquo; button to make a personal copy of this notebook. Make sure you are logged in to your Google account. If you are using a Nuevo Google account temporarily Once you make a copy, please make sure to replace the &amp;ldquo;Copy of&amp;rdquo; with your name, along with the file name.</description></item><item><title>Activity 4: Create Basic Filter</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-pixel/activities/activity-4/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-pixel/activities/activity-4/</guid><description>Now that we understand more about pixels and images, we can start to learn how to design your own filter on the image. Let us see some examples on how to design a basic filter on your image.
Example for blue filter We want to add a blue filter on the cute cat above. Let's see how to achieve that. # We need to import PIL package to allow manipulation with pixels.</description></item><item><title>Preload, Create, and Update</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/phaser-space-invaders-game/preload-create-update/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/phaser-space-invaders-game/preload-create-update/</guid><description>The Preload, Create, and Update methods So now let&amp;rsquo;s look at our scenes, which will eventually hold the code for our game. If you scroll through, you will see that each scene has a constructor (because it is a class), and also three large methods: preload(), create(), update(). There are also a number of helper functions in Scene 2, but we will talk about the aforementioned three methods because they are integral to understanding Phaser.</description></item><item><title>Properties</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/javascript-basics/arrays/properties/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/javascript-basics/arrays/properties/</guid><description>Array properties or characteristics are a way to describe the attributes of the array. Examples include: the total number of elements, the value at a particular index, etc&amp;hellip;
Here is a list of the properties of the Array object along with their description.
Constructor() Returns a reference to the array function that created the object.
Syntax:
arrayName.constructor; Example: Index() The property represents the zero-based index of the match in the string.</description></item><item><title>3. Update the Game Board</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-tictactoe/activity-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-tictactoe/activity-3/</guid><description>Prerequisites (from Java: Basics) activity-1: Print Statements and Comments activity-2: Variables and Types activity-4: Control Structures activity-5: Methods activity-6: Object and Classes activity-7: Data Structures (Array &amp;amp; ArrayList) These are the concepts from the Java: Basics workshop that we will use in this activity. Please refer to these activity to review or learn the concepts before continuing!
In the last exercise, we have a program that prints out the board and prompt Enter your move (1-9): to user with each valid move.</description></item><item><title>Nested loops</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/conditional-statements-loops/nested-loops/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/conditional-statements-loops/nested-loops/</guid><description>Nested loops To learn nested loops, you need to know simple for-loops and while loops. If you have already learnt them, you can skip to the next part. Otherwise, jump to a specific Python section to learn more about these topics:
For-loop and While-loop In this section, we will use one loop inside another, which is called nested loop. Nested while loop #This is the format for nested while loop while expressionA: while expressionB: statement(B) statement(A) In the while loop above, when expressionA produces False, we will skip the whole block.</description></item><item><title>Operators</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-basics/activity-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-basics/activity-3/</guid><description>1. Let&amp;rsquo;s do Math: Arithmetic Operator In the last exercise, we learn about variables any how we can assign values to a variable of a specific type, such as:
int age = 3; // declare variable age of type int with value 3 age = 4; // assign 4 to the variable age Looking at the code above, it essentially add 1 to the value of the variable age.</description></item><item><title>Load the bird image</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/jsappybird/load-the-bird/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/jsappybird/load-the-bird/</guid><description>First of all let&amp;rsquo;s load Flappy and put it on the screen.
Add below command in the file [File: load-sprites.js] game.load.image(&amp;lsquo;bird&amp;rsquo;,&amp;lsquo;assets/bird.png&amp;rsquo;);
Working Together In the repl.it window below, we started the code with the line game.load.image('bird', 'assets/bird.png');.
In your console you should see a Jsappy bird after you press run:</description></item><item><title>Variables</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/basics/variables/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/basics/variables/</guid><description>Variables are simply names that we can give to values such as strings, numbers, and booleans. Here’s how to make a variable named s. We say s is a string that has the value &amp;quot;Hello, World!&amp;quot;. Can you describe the following variables?
s = &amp;#34;Hello, World!&amp;#34; x = 88 happy = True Press run.
Note that variables are not printed out to the console. Instead, the variable simply saves the string, number, or boolean into the computer’s memory.</description></item><item><title>Activity 1 - Familiarize with online editor</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/web-basics/activity-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 17:53:41 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/web-basics/activity-1/</guid><description>Open the web editor (click the &amp;ldquo;Try it yourself!&amp;rdquo; button below) Use the header tags to add a title, and the paragraph tags to write a paragraph about Benji If you have time: write a list of Benji&amp;rsquo;s favorite treats: turkey, peanut butter, and string cheese Try it yourself!
Use this reference chart to try some html tags on your own.
Tag Description Example &amp;lt;html&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt; Describes an HTML Document.</description></item><item><title>Activity 2 - Change the color of objects in game.</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/pygame-pong/activity-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/pygame-pong/activity-2/</guid><description>Activity 2 Great! You just fixed the game&amp;rsquo;s boundary. Now, notice how everything inside the game looks black and white. Let&amp;rsquo;s give it some colors.
To do this, we need to modify the RGB values in COLOR attribute. RGB stands for RED, GREEN, BLUE. In a computer screen, you can modify the color of each pixel by modifying its RGB value. Every color can be represented by combination of different RGB values in it.</description></item><item><title>Activity 2 - Simplifying code with loops</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-turtle/activity-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-turtle/activity-2/</guid><description>Great! You drew a square. But notice that we are writing the same lines over and over again! We had to repeat the instructions to draw a line and turn left 4 times. Wouldn’t it be great if we can give instructions once and tell the program to repeat it 4 times? Fear not, we can!
To do this, we need to use loops. Loops run a set of instructions multiple times.</description></item><item><title>Interpreting Signal Strength</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/microbit-distance-checker/signal-strength/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/microbit-distance-checker/signal-strength/</guid><description>Now that our micro:bit knows how strong the signal it got is, we need to use that to figure out how close we are. Click on the Logic section and grab the &amp;ldquo;if true then / else&amp;rdquo; block. Drag that inside the radio received block, just under where we set the strength variable. Go back into the Logic section and drag the 0 = 0 comparison on top of the true on the &amp;ldquo;if true then&amp;rdquo; line.</description></item><item><title>Activity 1 - Write to console</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/csharp-guess-the-word/activity-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/csharp-guess-the-word/activity-1/</guid><description>Instructions Go to the code containing the GuessTheWord game. Press run. Notice that Press 'run' on the top of the screen to play again. is the only thing that is printed to the console. Let&amp;rsquo;s add a welcome message so that the player knows they playing the Guess the Word game.
Find // TODO (ACTIVITY 1) in the code. Add a line of code to print Welcome to C# GuessTheWord to the console.</description></item><item><title>Web Developer Guidelines</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/guidelines/web-developer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 14:08:32 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/guidelines/web-developer/</guid><description>This document is for website developers only for changing the Nuevo Foundation workshop project templates and style.
Before getting started Before adding/updating the website, ensure you have synced with the project team and the existing work in the Project Backlog.
Setup Follow the instructions in the Project readme.md to install Git and Hugo to test the project locally.
Web design styles and structure Images: Website images should be themes/images CSS Ignore the SCSS files and just use CSS files in /themes/docdock/static/css/ Make sure to add a reference to the CSS you want to include in the head.</description></item><item><title>Activity 1: Blinking LED</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/arduino/activity-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/arduino/activity-1/</guid><description>Wiring Our Blinking LED For your introduction to this system, we&amp;rsquo;re going to turn an LED on and OFF. From this we can get the basics of circuitry and how our program can run and manipulate components.
Attach the long lead (anode) of your LED to pin 25J and the short lead (cathode) anywhere in the blue [-] line. Attach a 220 resistor with one leg in 25H and the other anywhere in the red [+] line.</description></item><item><title>Downloading your program</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/adafruit/downloading-your-program/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/adafruit/downloading-your-program/</guid><description>At the bottom of your workspace you should see this bright pink download button next to the name of your program. You can name your program anything, here it’s called adafruit_musicalfruit. Click on the download button.
You should see a window popping up, asking where to save your file. It should default to the Downloads folder, if not, navigate to your downloads folder and save the file there.
Now you can plug your USB cable into the computer.</description></item><item><title>Getting started with Earsketch</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-earsketch/getting-started-earsketch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-earsketch/getting-started-earsketch/</guid><description>EarSketch is a free educational programming environment developed at Georgia Institute of Technology. We will be composing music using EarSketch today.
To make music, click on EarSketch to open it in a new tab.
Now, let&amp;rsquo;s get started. Click on Scripts icon on the left menu bar and select Create a new script. When prompted to enter the script name, enter myjam and click on Create button.</description></item><item><title>More about phishing</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security-phishing/other-phishing-types/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security-phishing/other-phishing-types/</guid><description>Alice goes on to explain different kinds of phishing scams other than the email phishing.
Smishing (SMS Phishing) Phishing conducted via Short Message Service (SMS), a telephone-based text messaging service. A smishing text, for example, attempts to entice a victim into revealing personal information via a link that leads to a phishing website. In the above image, an unknown sender texts you about free deals on iPads and lures you into clicking a malicious link.</description></item><item><title>Pixels on an Image</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-pixel/colors_and_pixels/pixel-on-image/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-pixel/colors_and_pixels/pixel-on-image/</guid><description>Pixels Pixels are a small area of color on a display screen. Images are formed by pixels on the screen. We can manipulate pixels by changing the RGB Value, which are essentially changing the value of red, green and blue color on each pixels. When we see the an image on the screen, it is made of huge numbers of tiny pixel. Each tiny pixels has its only unique position and color it displays.</description></item><item><title>Spy Game</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security/spy-game/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security/spy-game/</guid><description>From our last activity we learnt that a strong password is a combination of random characters (possibly having uppercase and lowercase letters), numbers and some special characters. Now it&amp;rsquo;s time to play Hacked or Safe!
From a list of passwords used by our Nuvi select the strongest password which cannot be hacked by Eve.
Can this password be Hacked? Yes No Can this password be Hacked? Yes No Can this password be Hacked?</description></item><item><title>Summary</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security/summary/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security/summary/</guid><description>Remember the characteristics of a strong password are: At least 8 characters - the more characters, the better A mixture of letters and numbers Inclusion of at least one special character, e.g., ! @ # ? ] Note: do not use &amp;lt; or &amp;gt; in your password, as both can cause problems in Web browsers A strong password is hard to guess, but it should be easy for you to remember - a password that has to be written down is not strong, no matter how many of the above characteristics are employed.</description></item><item><title>Printing to Console</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/android-tictactoe/printconsole/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 14:17:07 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/android-tictactoe/printconsole/</guid><description>Sometimes the game or application might not work the way you expect it to or you want to write something to the console for logging purposes. Outside of debugging the application, you can use System.out.println() to write your message. Lookout for your messages in the &amp;ldquo;logcat&amp;rdquo; window at the bottom of Android Studio: Working Together Without removing the quotation marks, try changing &amp;quot;Restarting the Tac-Tic-Toe Game!&amp;quot; to &amp;quot;Restarting the Tic-Tac-Toe Game!</description></item><item><title>Activity 2 - Determine User Location</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/activity-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/activity-2/</guid><description>So before we can stop the hackers, we need to learn to navigate the Linux filesystem.
Where in the file system are you? The Linux command pwd will display your current location. This stands for Print Working Directory
Try it:
pwd The output above is /home/nuvi and its meaning is explained below:
/: This denotes the root directory, which is the beginning of the Linux file system. home: This denotes the home directory, which is located within the root directory.</description></item><item><title>Answer Key - Linux Basics</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/answerkey/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/answerkey/</guid><description>Activity 1 whoami Activity 2 pwd cd Desktop cd.. Activity 3 ls -l mv Documents/ Downloads/ ls -l Downloads mv Downloads/Documents/ . Activity 4 mkdir files touch file1 vim file1 mv file1 files Activity 5 chmod u=rwx g=rx o=x file1 chmod 751 [insert filename] Activity 6 cd grep -R &amp;quot;Do. Or do not. There is no try.&amp;quot; find . -name *.sh Activity 7 head -n 5 malware.sh tail -n 5 malware.</description></item><item><title>Activity 3 - Displaying Clothing Samples</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-tensorflow/activity-3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 16:19:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-tensorflow/activity-3/</guid><description>Now, you will be displaying all of your clothing samples by doing the following:
Copy the following code into your Colab notebook. This displays a collection of images along with their specific category.
plt.figure(figsize=(10,10)) #sets the image size to 10x10 pixels for i in range(25): #displays first 25 images with their class name plt.subplot(5,5,i+1) plt.xticks([]) plt.yticks([]) plt.grid(False) plt.imshow(train_images[i], cmap=plt.cm.binary) plt.xlabel(class_names[train_labels[i]]) plt.show() #shows images with their labels Question 1 Your supervisor hands you out around 15-20 more clothing samples, which you will have to include in your program.</description></item><item><title>Activity 5: More advanced filters</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-pixel/activities/activity-5/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-pixel/activities/activity-5/</guid><description>In the last section, we saw an example of creating a blue filter and thought about how to create the grey filter. Now, let us create our grey filter together.
Example - Create a grey filter Let us change the original cat image below with our grey filter together!
# We need to import PIL package to allow manipulation with pixels. from PIL import Image # Open the cat image img = Image.</description></item><item><title>Placing Things into Phaser</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/phaser-space-invaders-game/placing-things/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/phaser-space-invaders-game/placing-things/</guid><description>Placing Text Now, you will learn how to place things within Phaser. Look at the repl below.
Let&amp;rsquo;s first go over how to place text!
message = this.add.text(20, 10, &amp;#34;Hello World!&amp;#34;, { font: &amp;#34;25px Arial&amp;#34;, fill: &amp;#34;white&amp;#34; }); These lines of code create a variable named &amp;ldquo;message.&amp;rdquo; This variable adds the text &amp;ldquo;Hello World&amp;rdquo; to the (X, Y) coordinate (20, 10) on our game window. The code also specifices that the text is created to be the color white, have font Arial, and have font size 25 px.</description></item><item><title>Formatting</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/guidelines/formatting/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 14:08:32 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/guidelines/formatting/</guid><description>Formatting Reference Standard Markdown cheatsheet Custom Formatting Options using shortcodes Formatting Examples This theme includes a number of options to customize the look and feel of your site.
Alerts Info {{% alert theme=&amp;quot;info&amp;quot; %}}**This** is an info {{% /alert %}} role=&amp;quot;alert&amp;quot;&amp;gt;This is an info
Success {{% alert theme=&amp;quot;success&amp;quot; %}}**Yeahhh !** is a success{{% /alert %}} role=&amp;quot;alert&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Yeahhh ! is a success
Warning {{% alert theme=&amp;quot;warning&amp;quot; %}}**Be careful** is a warning{{% /alert %}} role=&amp;quot;alert&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Be careful is a warning</description></item><item><title>Change the screen text</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/jsappybird/change-screen-text/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/jsappybird/change-screen-text/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s change the start screen text:
Add below command in the file [File: start-screen.js] var text = game.add.text(0, 0, &amp;ldquo;Press Space to Start&amp;rdquo;, textOptions);
Working Together In the repl.it window below, we started the code with the line var text = game.add.text(0, 0, &amp;quot;Press Space to Start&amp;quot;, textOptions);.
In your console you should see Press Space to Start after you press run:</description></item><item><title>4. Check the winner</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-tictactoe/activity-4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-tictactoe/activity-4/</guid><description>Prerequisites (from Java: Basics) activity-1: Print Statements and Comments activity-2: Variables and Types activity-3: Operators activity-4: Control Structures activity-5: Methods activity-6: Object and Classes activity-7: Data Structures (Array &amp;amp; ArrayList) These are the concepts from the Java: Basics workshop that we will use in this activity. Please refer to these activity to review or learn the concepts before continuing!
1. Displaying a Winner Write a method getWinner(String[] curBoard) that returns the winner in a String with an array input of the current game board.</description></item><item><title>Control Structures</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-basics/activity-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-basics/activity-4/</guid><description>1. Make a Decision: If-Statement Patrick 🐥 is a very polite duck who likes to greet everyone he meets with &amp;ldquo;Good Morning,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Good Afternoon,&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Good Night&amp;rdquo; depends on the current time.
(image by National Geographic: giphy.com/natgeochannel)
As we learned before, we can print these statements as below:
System.out.println(&amp;#34;Good Morning&amp;#34;); // say it between 0:00 - 11:59 System.out.println(&amp;#34;Good Afternoon&amp;#34;); // say it between 12:00 - 19:59 System.out.println(&amp;#34;Good Night&amp;#34;); // say it between 20:00 - 23:59 However, we also know Patrick 🐥 should only decide to say one of these statements depends on the time.</description></item><item><title>HTML Attributes</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/web-basics/html-attributes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 17:53:41 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/web-basics/html-attributes/</guid><description>HTML Attributes Each tag can also have additional information like style attributes that can change the properties of an element. There are attributes that we can use to change the visual appearance of an element, such as the size, the color, and the text font.
All attributes are formatted as: attribute-name=&amp;quot;value in quotes&amp;quot;. For example, we can change the color of a paragraph to red with this code: &amp;lt;p style=&amp;quot;color:red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;This text is red&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;.</description></item><item><title>Activity 3 - Change the key assignment to move left paddle</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/pygame-pong/activity-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/pygame-pong/activity-3/</guid><description>Activity 3 Kudos! You not only fixed the game boundary, but you are able to give color to objects too. Now, let&amp;rsquo;s see if you can change the keys for paddle movement.
To do this, we need to modify one of the parameters we passed in when creating the left paddle object. Remember from the basics section, you defined the Paddle class with UP and DOWN key assignments as its attributes.</description></item><item><title>Activity 3 - Drawing a hexagon</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-turtle/activity-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-turtle/activity-3/</guid><description>Great job! You just drew your first shape in Python with Turtle! Now let’s slightly change the code we already wrote to draw a square to instead draw a hexagon. Alex is a bee, after all, and he needs to draw hexagons to build his first honeycomb.
To help you draw a hexagon, think of how many sides a hexagon has. How many degrees are in each angle of a hexagon?</description></item><item><title>Lighting it up</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/microbit-distance-checker/light-it-up/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/microbit-distance-checker/light-it-up/</guid><description>We have all our logic written, but no way to tell if we&amp;rsquo;re more than 6 feet apart. Now we&amp;rsquo;ll add some lights so we can actually see when we&amp;rsquo;re far enough apart. Click the Basic section at the top and drag a &amp;ldquo;show icon&amp;rdquo; block into the if part of our logic block. Click on the icon to see a list of other icons and choose the sad, frowning face.</description></item><item><title>Strings</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/csharp-guess-the-word/strings/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/csharp-guess-the-word/strings/</guid><description>Strings Anything that is surrounded in quotation marks is called a string. This is how a computer represents words or sentences. For example, &amp;quot;a&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;2&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;banana!&amp;quot;, and &amp;quot;Hello World&amp;quot; are strings, but Hello World and 2 are not strings, because the quotation marks are missing.
You can combine many strings together using the + operator. For example:
&amp;quot;Apple&amp;quot; + &amp;quot;Pineapple&amp;quot; produces the string &amp;quot;ApplePineapple&amp;quot;. &amp;quot;Nuevo&amp;quot; + &amp;quot; &amp;quot; + &amp;quot;Foundation&amp;quot; produces the string &amp;quot;Nuevo Foundation&amp;quot;.</description></item><item><title>Access pixels on image</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-pixel/colors_and_pixels/access-pixel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-pixel/colors_and_pixels/access-pixel/</guid><description>More about pixels We have already learned how to make a pure color image using pixels and change a pixel on the image. Now, we will learn how to identify pixels in existing images.
For information about how to use lists and tuples in Python see more on these pages: Data Structure Get image data # Remember to import Image from PIL import Image Image.size Image.size[0] Image.size[1] Image.</description></item><item><title>Activity 1 - Set tempo &amp; add sounds</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-earsketch/activity-1-set-tempo-add-sounds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-earsketch/activity-1-set-tempo-add-sounds/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s take a closer look at the pre-existing code and understand what it means. We will be placing our new code between the setTempo() and finish() functions. The setTempo() function allows you to set the overall project tempo.
Quick Fact: Tempo is the speed at which a piece of music is played. Changing a project&amp;rsquo;s tempo allows for different styles of music to be created. Try changing the tempo of your setTempo function and see what happens!</description></item><item><title>Activity 2 - Joystick with Serial Output</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/arduino/activity-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/arduino/activity-2/</guid><description>Wiring the Joystick Now that you understand how we can get the system to provide signals from the program (outputs) and use those to control LEDs, let’s look at how we can get dynamic inputs into the system. For this activity we will use a joystick input, similar to those used in video game consoles.
Attach one end of a jumper wire to GND on the joystick and the other to GND on the Elegoo.</description></item><item><title>Answer Key - Adafruit</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/adafruit/answer-key/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/adafruit/answer-key/</guid><description>Setup In summary:
The two alligator clips should be clipped into the surface of the oranges. The other side of the clips should be on the A1 and A2 inputs on the adafruit. The USB should be plugged in to the adafruit, but not into the computer. After setup, the oranges and adafruit should look like this:
Solution Solution - advanced (with lights) How it Works</description></item><item><title>Answer Key - Security</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security/answer-key/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security/answer-key/</guid><description>Solution In our Spy Game the passwords &amp;ldquo;Ilovemypet&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;12345678&amp;rdquo; are weak and can be easily hacked/guessed by a malicious person.</description></item><item><title>What's Phishy?</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security-phishing/whats-phishy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security-phishing/whats-phishy/</guid><description>From our last section we learned about different types of phishing methods and how to recognize them. Now it&amp;rsquo;s time to play a game called What's phishy?
From a list of images given below choose whether you think it&amp;rsquo;s phishy or not?
Does this email look phishy? Yes No Does this email look phishy? Yes No -- Does this banner look phishy? Yes No Does this text message look phishy?</description></item><item><title>Puzzle 2</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/android-tictactoe/puzzle2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 14:17:07 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/android-tictactoe/puzzle2/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s add a welcome message that the user can see when they start your app!
Go to MainActivity.kt and find // PUZZLE 2 in the code and write a toast that welcomes the user to your game with &amp;ldquo;Welcome to Tic-Tac-Toe!”. Now press the play button (►) at the top of Android Studio and your app should look like this:
HELP! I got a lot of red text! If you see any red text, you have encountered some errors!</description></item><item><title>Activity 3 - Explore Current Directory</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/activity-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/activity-3/</guid><description>Now that we know who and where we are, let&amp;rsquo;s take a look around for signs of the hackers.
How do you explore the directory? To see the Files in the current directory, we use the ls command.
Try it:
ls -l The -l flag in the above command tells ls to list long form information.
What information is being displayed? Let&amp;rsquo;s examine the top line of the example above from left to right, for the directory Desktop:</description></item><item><title>Building the Neural Network</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-tensorflow/building_neural_network/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 16:19:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-tensorflow/building_neural_network/</guid><description>This is the first step in building a neural network, which is actually a tool to allow us to do &amp;ldquo;machine learning&amp;rdquo;. With this tool, we are training a model/computer to analyze various training images/data, likely labeled in advance, and perform and execute a specific task as a result. In our scenario, we are using pre-labeled images of clothing to train our model to correctly predict the type of clothing for any clothing sample we input.</description></item><item><title>Activity 6: Crop Image</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-pixel/activities/activity-6/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-pixel/activities/activity-6/</guid><description>In this section, we will start to learn how to crop your image.
Example - Crop cat into half Now, let us crop out the right half of the cat image
# We need to import PIL package to allow manipulation with pixels. from PIL import Image # Open the cat image img = Image.open(&amp;#34;cat.png&amp;#34;) width = img.size[0] height = img.size[1] # Set up a new image with the half width and height newimg = Image.</description></item><item><title>Activity 1 - Place Background and Player Ship</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/phaser-space-invaders-game/activity-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/phaser-space-invaders-game/activity-1/</guid><description>This activity will have two parts: loading in the game&amp;rsquo;s background and loading in the ship that the player will eventually control (it will just be an image that doesn&amp;rsquo;t move for now). For both of these activities, the method will be very similar: we will first upload the image into the game on Scene 1 and then make it visible with Scene 2. You can think of Scene 1 as being used to upload the picture into the game and Scene 2 being used to create things that we&amp;rsquo;ve uploaded.</description></item><item><title>Iterating over Arrays</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/javascript-basics/arrays/iteration/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/javascript-basics/arrays/iteration/</guid><description>One of the common array operations is to iterate over the values and process each one of them in some way. Let&amp;rsquo;s go over and discuss some of the simplest ways to achieve this:
Array.forEach() The forEach() method calls a function (a callback function. In this case, function named printBr) once for each array element.
The function passed to forEach is executed once for every item in the array, with the array item passed as the argument to the function.</description></item><item><title>5. (Optional) AI Move</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-tictactoe/activity-5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-tictactoe/activity-5/</guid><description>This is a bonus activity! To continue, you should have completed the Tic-Tac-Toe program from the previous exercises!
Prerequisites (from Java: Basics) activity-1: Print Statements and Comments activity-2: Variables and Types activity-3: Operators activity-4: Control Structures activity-5: Methods activity-6: Object and Classes activity-7: Data Structures (Array &amp;amp; ArrayList)
Let&amp;rsquo;s make the computer think Previously, we use a Random object to randomly generate a move for the computer. As a result, the competitiveness of the computer is fairly low.</description></item><item><title>Methods</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-basics/activity-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-basics/activity-5/</guid><description>1. What is A Method? So far, we&amp;rsquo;ve learned about how to store data in variables, print data and sentences, and make decisions with if-statement, for-loop, and while-loop.
From the last exercise, we know the following block of code calculates the sum from 1 to 100:
int total = 0; int num = 1; while(num &amp;lt;= 100){ total = total + num; num = num + 1; } System.out.println(&amp;#34;Sum: &amp;#34; + total); But what if we want to calculate the sum from 1 to 77 instead?</description></item><item><title>Make the bird jump</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/jsappybird/jump/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/jsappybird/jump/</guid><description>What should we do with the bird?
Let&amp;rsquo;s make him jump:
Add below command in the file [File: create-game.js] spaceKey.onDown.add(jump, this);
Working Together In the repl.it window below, we started the code with the line spaceKey.onDown.add(jump, this);.
In your console you should see a Jsappy bird jumping after you press run:</description></item><item><title>Reading from the Console</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/basics/reading-from-console/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/basics/reading-from-console/</guid><description>Now that we know the basics about variables, we can ask for input from the user. Use the following line to tell our program to wait until the user types something into the console. Then, the computer takes whatever is typed into the console, and stores it into the variable called value.
value = input Here&amp;rsquo;s and examples of how to use input() to accept user input:
print(&amp;#34;What&amp;#39;s your name?&amp;#34;) value = input() print(&amp;#34;Hello &amp;#34; + value + &amp;#34;!</description></item><item><title>Activity 2 - CSS</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/web-basics/activity-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 17:53:41 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/web-basics/activity-2/</guid><description>Style it with CSS Tags tell the browser what website elements to use. But we also need to tell it how to display the elements, and where to place them. We may want the title on the center or on the right side. We may want a picture on the right and a paragraph on the left. There are two ways we can do this: through HTML attributes or Cascading Style Sheets.</description></item><item><title>Activity 4 - Change the key assignment to move right paddle.</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/pygame-pong/activity-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/pygame-pong/activity-4/</guid><description>Activity 4 Now you know how to change key assignments to control a paddle&amp;rsquo;s movement. Great work!
We have added movement for the left paddle. Can you apply the knowledge about the Paddle object and its attributes that influence its movement on screen to change the key assignment for the right paddle?
Find // TODO (ACTIVITY 4) in the code. Modify the appropriate attribute value for the right paddle such that pressing the 'UP' key moves the right paddle up.</description></item><item><title>Activity 4 - Simplifying code with functions</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-turtle/activity-4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-turtle/activity-4/</guid><description>We drew one hexagon. But this is just one of many hexagons Alex needs to build his honeycomb. Once again, it seems that we would have to repeat the code many times to draw multiple hexagons. Fortunately, we don&amp;rsquo;t have to! Functions to the rescue!
Functions A function is a way to group together lines of code to do something. For instance, turtle.forward(50) moves the turtle forward 50 steps, and turtle.</description></item><item><title>Downloading the code and trying it out</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/microbit-distance-checker/running-code/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/microbit-distance-checker/running-code/</guid><description>Now that our code has been written, it&amp;rsquo;s time to try it all out. First, we have to pair the micro:bit with a computer. Find your USB cable and connect the smaller side to the silver USB port on the top of your micro:bit. Connect the other, larger end to a USB port on your computer. On the MakeCode workspace, click the ellipsis (&amp;hellip;) next to the Download button to make a small menu pop up.</description></item><item><title>Activity 2 - Add words to the word bank</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/csharp-guess-the-word/activity-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/csharp-guess-the-word/activity-2/</guid><description>Instructions Find // TODO (ACTIVITY 2) in the GuessTheWord code. For the Guess the Word game, we will give the computer a word bank, and the computer will choose one of the words randomly to use for the game. So far, we have added the words &amp;quot;Hello&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;World&amp;quot; to the word bank. However, a Guess the Word game with only two possible words to guess is not fun at all!</description></item><item><title>Activity 2 - Make a song!</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-earsketch/activity-2-make-a-song/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-earsketch/activity-2-make-a-song/</guid><description>Now that you have learned how to add sounds to Earsketch, let&amp;rsquo;s try and make a song! You should already have one audio clip in Earsketch, but songs are made up of various instruments, so we need to add more audio clips.
Add another fitMedia() call. Find an audio clip you would like to add to your current song and input it under the fileName parameter. The trackNumber parameter should be a unique number.</description></item><item><title>Activity 3 - Joystick &amp; LEDs</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/arduino/activity-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/arduino/activity-3/</guid><description>Activity 3 - Joystick + LEDs Let’s combine activity 1 and activity 2. Let’s control LEDs based on the input from the joystick.
Attach one end of a jumper wire to GND on the joystick and the other to 7X on the Breadboard. Attach one end of a jumper wire to +5V on the joystick and the other to 5W on the Breadboard. Attach one end of a jumper wire to VRx on the joystick and the other to A0 on the Elegoo.</description></item><item><title>Summary</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security-phishing/summary/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security-phishing/summary/</guid><description>Conclusion In conclusion, the common features found in Phishing scams have at least one of the following properties:
Lucrative offers or attention grabbing statements. Unusual sender of unexpected behavior or character. Sense of urgency by asking you to act fast because of limited time offers or deals. Example: Your password is about to expire click here to change it immediately. Suspicious hyperlinks. Hovering over the link will show the actual URL you will be directed to.</description></item><item><title>Comments</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/android-tictactoe/comments/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 14:17:07 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/android-tictactoe/comments/</guid><description>Developers often need to collaborate with other developers. Comments are an easy way for developers to write notes in the code and communicate with others. Comments are ignored by the computer; thus, they are also an easy way to tell the computer to not run certain lines of code. There are two ways to create comments:
To comment out one line, place // in front of a line of code.</description></item><item><title>Activity 4 - Note Taking Practice</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/activity-4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/activity-4/</guid><description>As a cybersecurity engineer, it is important to take a lot of notes. These are helpful for future reference to understand how the hack happened. Let&amp;rsquo;s step up our workspace!
What if I want to create a new directory? To practice creating a new directory, use the command mkdir in the following format: mkdir new_directory_name.
Lets make a directory called files by typing the command below:
mkdir files As you can see, now when ls -l is run, an additional directory named files appears</description></item><item><title>Activity 4 - Training the Model</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-tensorflow/activity-4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 16:19:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-tensorflow/activity-4/</guid><description>The following code determines how many times model is trained. It is normal for this segment of code to take longer than usual to run.
model.fit(train_images, train_labels, epochs=10) The following code prints out the overall test accuracy.
test_loss, test_acc = model.evaluate(test_images, test_labels, verbose=2) print(&amp;#39;\nTest accuracy:&amp;#39;, test_acc) Question 1 Set the value of epochs equal to 2. What is the accuracy of the last epoch? What is the test accuracy when the trained model is compared to the test dataset?</description></item><item><title>Activity 7: Change the background of image</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-pixel/activities/activity-7/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-pixel/activities/activity-7/</guid><description>In this section, we will start to learn how to change the simple background of your image using pixels.
Example - Change background color Let us change the background color of Nuvi to pink. from PIL import Image # Open the Nuvi image img = Image.open(&amp;#34;nuevo.png&amp;#34;) width = img.size[0] height = img.size[1] # Set up a new image with width and height newimg = Image.new(&amp;#39;RGB&amp;#39;,(width,height)) # Set the pixels for the new image colorpink = (244,114,208) coloryellow = img.</description></item><item><title>Creating Animations</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/phaser-space-invaders-game/animation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/phaser-space-invaders-game/animation/</guid><description>Animation in Phaser Animation works by showing a set of images back to back very quickly. When we do this quickly, our mind sees it as movement. In a way, you&amp;rsquo;re tricking the mind to think that this set of images is just one thing that is moving.
We use spritesheets for things we want to be animated because we can create that animation by scrolling through the spritesheets. In order to animate spritesheets, there are two steps we must do.</description></item><item><title>Object and Classes</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-basics/activity-6/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-basics/activity-6/</guid><description>1. Creating a Class! Java is an object-oriented programming language, which means everything in Java is associated with an object and a class (the blueprint for the object).
For starters, the line of code that we used to print statements from activity 1 is actually a method call from a predefined class called System!
System.out.println(&amp;#34;Hello World&amp;#34;); System is a class that deals with user input and outputs. out is a variable in class System of the class/type PrintStream.</description></item><item><title>Add gravity</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/jsappybird/gravity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/jsappybird/gravity/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s add gravity to the bird:
Add below command in the file [File: create-game.js] bird.body.gravity.y = 900;
Working Together In the repl.it window below, we started the code with the line bird.body.gravity.y = 900;.
In your console you should see a JSappy bird jumping with gravity after you press run:</description></item><item><title>Media Elements</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/web-basics/media-elements/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 17:53:41 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/web-basics/media-elements/</guid><description>Add a GIF GIF stands for Graphic Interchange Format, but all you need to know is that it&amp;rsquo;s just another type of image file. The only difference is that the file has many images. When displayed in the browser, the images are played in sequence, similar to the frames of a movie. Think of it like one of those flip books that seem like the image is animated when you flip it.</description></item><item><title>Activity 5 - Declare and use a variable for font</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/pygame-pong/activity-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/pygame-pong/activity-5/</guid><description>Activity 5 Great progress so far! Now let&amp;rsquo;s make use of a variable to change the font of the text in the game.
In this activity, you need to apply the knowledge about variables you learned in Python basics.
Find // TODO (ACTIVITY 5) in the code. Declare the variable font_label, assign it the value 'arial'. Now take a look at this statement in the code font_name = pygame.font.match_font('arial'). Can you figure out the place in this statement where you should use this new variable to control the font displayed on screen?</description></item><item><title>Activity 5 - Drawing a honeycomb</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-turtle/activity-5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-turtle/activity-5/</guid><description>This is the finale! Let&amp;rsquo;s create the honeycomb that Alex will live in. Fortunately, a honeycomb is simply 6 hexagons, so let&amp;rsquo;s combine our knowledge of functions and loops to make our honeycomb!
In this activity, create a new function called draw_honeycomb(). Inside the function body, create a loop that repeats 6 times. Inside the loop we have to first draw a hexagon using our draw_hexagon() function we previously defined. Next, move the turtle so it can draw the next hexagon.</description></item><item><title>Numbers</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/csharp-guess-the-word/numbers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/csharp-guess-the-word/numbers/</guid><description>Numbers The computer can also do regular math that you see in school. Use Console.WriteLine to print out the result from the math expressions. No quotation marks are needed for numbers!
Console.WriteLine(5 + 4); Console.WriteLine(6 * (9 - 7) / 3); Here is the full list of math symbols that you can use:
Operator Description Operator Description + Add \ | Divide | - Subtract % Modulo (remainder) * Multiply (,) Parenthesis Fun Fact: Computer Division The computer does division differently from your regular calculator.</description></item><item><title>Activity 3 - Organize your song using functions</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-earsketch/activity-3-organize-songs-using-functions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-earsketch/activity-3-organize-songs-using-functions/</guid><description>In Earsketch, functions are mostly used to organize different sections of a song. The most common musical form is A-B-A where each section is four measures in length, and the A sections sound different from the B section.
Now that we learned how to use functions, let&amp;rsquo;s try to use them to organize our songs better.
Define your function with a startMeasure parameter and endMeasure parameter. Place the sounds you would like to have the function represent underneath your function definition.</description></item><item><title>Activity 4 - LCD Display</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/arduino/activity-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/arduino/activity-4/</guid><description>Wiring Diagram Now that you have mastered outputting signals to LEDs let’s look at displaying text with a simple display. Only 1 resistor (5K) is used to limit the brightness of the display. Try wiring this per the diagram without specific instructions.
The Code: //www.elegoo.com
//2016.12.9
/*
LiquidCrystal Library - Hello World
Demonstrates the use a 16x2 LCD display. The LiquidCrystal
library works with all LCD displays that are compatible with the
Hitachi HD44780 driver.</description></item><item><title>Strings</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/android-tictactoe/strings/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 14:17:07 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/android-tictactoe/strings/</guid><description>Anything that is surrounded in quotation marks is called a string. This is how a computer represents words or sentences. For example, &amp;quot;a&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;2&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;banana!&amp;quot;, and &amp;quot;Hello World&amp;quot; are strings, but Hello World and 2 are not strings, because the quotation marks are missing. You can combine many strings together using the + operator. For example:
&amp;quot;Apple&amp;quot; + &amp;quot;Pineapple&amp;quot; produces the string &amp;quot;ApplePineapple&amp;quot;. &amp;quot;Nuevo&amp;quot; + &amp;quot; &amp;quot; + &amp;quot;Foundation&amp;quot; produces the string &amp;quot;Nuevo Foundation&amp;quot;.</description></item><item><title>Activity 5 - Secure User Permissions</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/activity-5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/activity-5/</guid><description>Oh no. Some of our files might have been messed with! Let’s secure our notes, file1. We don&amp;rsquo;t want a hacker to mess with these!
But, How do we know how secure our files are? Is there a command that we have learned so far that can show us how secure our files are?
Feel free to go back if you need to!
We should keep using that command to check if we changed the permissions as expected.</description></item><item><title>Activity 5 - Testing the Model</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-tensorflow/activity-5/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 16:19:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-tensorflow/activity-5/</guid><description>Now that we have built and trained our model, we want to go ahead and test it against returned clothing items. Let&amp;rsquo;s start off with our first sample item, which was the shoe.
probability_model = tf.keras.Sequential([model, tf.keras.layers.Softmax()]) predictions = probability_model.predict(test_images) The following code gives a list of probabilities that an image fits in a specific category. The index value corresponds to what image would be classified.
predictions[0] #Returns the index with highest probability, depends on the index value.</description></item><item><title>Activity 8: Flip your image</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-pixel/activities/activity-8/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-pixel/activities/activity-8/</guid><description>In this section, we will start to learn how to flip your image using pixels.
Example - Flip your image upside down Let us flip the cat upside down. Flipping the image upside down is the same as creating a symmetrical image with respect to the horizontal central line, which is the black line in the following image.
# We need to import PIL package to manipulation with pixels.</description></item><item><title>Activity 2 - Animating the Player's Ship</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/phaser-space-invaders-game/activity-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/phaser-space-invaders-game/activity-2/</guid><description>To add some life to our game, let’s get things moving around! Animate the player we have created.
Once your ship is animated, it should look like this. Notice the flames coming out of the ship&amp;rsquo;s engine! (although it may be faster or slower depending on the frame rate that you picked)
We will make one final touch to the animation - we will move the background as well. Change the background from a regular image to a TileSprite like this:</description></item><item><title>Make the bird jump with force</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/jsappybird/jump-force/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/jsappybird/jump-force/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s add force to the bird
Add the below command in the file [File: create-game.js] bird.body.velocity.y = -350;
Working Together In the repl.it window below, we started the code with the line bird.body.velocity.y = -350;.
In your console you should see a Jsappy bird jumping with force after you press run:
Bonus Activity Let&amp;rsquo;s make the bird jump up and forwards:
Add below command in the file [File: create-game.js] bird.body.velocity.x = 100;</description></item><item><title>Methods</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/javascript-basics/arrays/methods/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/javascript-basics/arrays/methods/</guid><description>Methods represent some action we wish to perform on the array. They can be used to change the behaviour or perform some operations on itself.
To make things easier, arrays provide a lot of methods. Let&amp;rsquo;s go over some of the basic ones which would give you an idea of they look like.
How is it different compared to properties ? Properties are basically information that an array has. Methods are what an array can do.</description></item><item><title>Data Structures (Array &amp; ArrayList)</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-basics/activity-7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-basics/activity-7/</guid><description>In previous exercises, we learned that variables allow us to access and store a piece data. But, what if we want to store a bunch of similiar data? Is there a good way to organize them without declaring multiple variables?
In programming, data structures are structures that allowed coders to store multiple pieces of data of the same type. Using data structures is an efficient way to store and access large pieces of data.</description></item><item><title>Activity 3 - Adding a GIF of Nuvi</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/web-basics/activity-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 17:53:41 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/web-basics/activity-3/</guid><description> Follow this link to see the available GIFs Click on the one you like and select &amp;ldquo;Embed&amp;rdquo; Copy the code from the white box below &amp;ldquo;GIF Embed Code&amp;quot;
Paste the code anywhere in your page as long as it&amp;rsquo;s inside the &amp;lt;body&amp;gt; tags.
Try it yourself!</description></item><item><title>Activity 6 - Fix the 'if' condition to track correct score.</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/pygame-pong/activity-6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/pygame-pong/activity-6/</guid><description>Activity 6 You have come a long way; we hope you are enjoying this workshop!
In this activity, you need to apply your knowledge of &amp;lsquo;if&amp;rsquo; control structures you learned in the Python basics workshop.
Find // TODO (ACTIVITY 6) in the code. We introduced an 'if' block on purpose that has the wrong condition for tracking the score when the right paddle misses the ball. This not only causes the wrong score to be displayed on screen; it causes the ball to move in an erratic manner.</description></item><item><title>Part 2 - Building a Mandala Flower</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-turtle/part-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-turtle/part-2/</guid><description>Great job! You finished building a honeycomb for Alex’s beehive, but Alex needs to also get his pollen from flowers! Wouldn’t it be nice to add a flower to the picture as well? In part 2, we will be creating a mandala flower!
(Stay tuned - we&amp;rsquo;ll show you what a mandala flower looks like.)</description></item><item><title>Booleans</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/csharp-guess-the-word/booleans/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/csharp-guess-the-word/booleans/</guid><description>Booleans Booleans are true or false statements. Unlike strings or numbers, booleans store statements of truth: is what I am saying true or false? For example, if I ask, &amp;ldquo;Are you a robot?&amp;quot;, this question produces a true or false result, which we call a Boolean. In this case, since you are not a robot (hopefully!), we would produce false.
We can also use math operators to create boolean expressions. Here are some examples; however, notice the unusual symbols for &amp;ldquo;equal to&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;not equal to&amp;rdquo;:</description></item><item><title>Activity 4 - Add effects to your song</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-earsketch/activity-4-add-effects-to-your-songs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-earsketch/activity-4-add-effects-to-your-songs/</guid><description>Effects in EarSketch Effects allows the producer to alter the sound of the audio clip into its own unique sound. Similar to how we used fitMedia() to add new audio clips, we must use the setEffect() function to define specific effects for each audio clip. It is important to note that multiple effects can be placed on the same track. This allows for the producer to combine multiple effects together.</description></item><item><title>Numbers</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/android-tictactoe/numbers/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 14:17:07 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/android-tictactoe/numbers/</guid><description>The computer can also do regular math that you see in school. Use System.out.println to print out the result from the math expressions.
System.out.println(5 + 4); System.out.println(6 * (9 - 7) / 3); Here is the full list of math symbols that you can use:
+ Add \ Divide - Subtract % Modulo (remainder) * Multiply (,) Parenthesis Fun Fact: Computer Division
The computer does division differently from your regular calculator.</description></item><item><title>Activity 6 - A BAD File</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/activity-6/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/activity-6/</guid><description>I know I had a file secret-message.txt with one of my favorite quotes in it. &amp;ldquo;Do. Or do not. There is no try.&amp;rdquo; Can you help me find it?
Searching for a pattern in a file? grep is a command used to search for a pattern of chars. There are different flags or options that can change how it is used.
The format is: grep [flag] “[pattern]” [filename].
A char is any letter, symbol, or number.</description></item><item><title>Activity 6 - Testing the Model</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-tensorflow/activity-6/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 16:19:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-tensorflow/activity-6/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s repeat the same thing with the second clothing sample you chose in Activity 2. Change the index value to the one used for the second image in Activity 2. Then, repeat Activity 5 starting from predictions[your_index_value]</description></item><item><title>Activity 9: Rotate your image</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-pixel/activities/activity-9/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-pixel/activities/activity-9/</guid><description>In this section, we will start to learn how to rotate your image using pixels.
Example - Rotate your image 180 degree clock-wise Let us rotate our cat 180 degrees clock-wise. # We need to import PIL package to allow manipulation with pixels. from PIL import Image # Open the cat image img = Image.open(&amp;#34;cat.png&amp;#34;) width = img.size[0] height = img.size[1] # Set up a new image with the half width and height newimg = Image.</description></item><item><title>Enabling User Inputs</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/phaser-space-invaders-game/input/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/phaser-space-invaders-game/input/</guid><description>User Inputs Inputs are essential because without the user inputting things with controls, our game isn&amp;rsquo;t really much of a game. Although Phaser supports a variety of different input options, we are going to go over three that you will use in the Space Invaders Game.
Arrow Keys Let&amp;rsquo;s start with one of the most important controls: arrow keys. First, we will create a variable that is able to detect when the player presses an arrow key.</description></item><item><title>Bird falling with rotation</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/jsappybird/add-rotation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/jsappybird/add-rotation/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s add rotation to the bird:
Add below command in the file [File: update-game.js] if (bird.angle &amp;lt; 50) { bird.angle += 1; }
Comments: If is a conditional block where we are checking the angle of the bird and if it&amp;rsquo;s less than 50 we are executing the condition. -bird.angle+=1;
Working Together In the repl.it window below, we started the code with the line bird.angle +=1;.
In your console you should see a Jsappy bird rotating with an angle after you press run:</description></item><item><title>Activity 4 - Try the form and change the style</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/web-basics/activity-4/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 17:53:41 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/web-basics/activity-4/</guid><description>Adding a Contact Form Finally, we will add a contact form to let people reach us if they are interested in Benji.
Most browsers do not support sending emails directly from the contact form because it&amp;rsquo;s an easy way for trouble makers to send spam to users. Spam is an irrelevant or inappropriate message sent over the internet. Therefore, to send a form, we will use a free service called FormSpree.</description></item><item><title>Activity 7 - Define the key combination to exit the game</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/pygame-pong/activity-7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/pygame-pong/activity-7/</guid><description>Activity 7 Time for the final activity in this workshop; yay! You have done an awesome job getting here. You should be proud of yourself!
In this activity, you need to change the way the game exits anytime a given key combination is pressed.
Find // TODO (ACTIVITY 7) in the code. The Pygame library gives you a handy way by using event to detect what keystrokes are being pressed anytime during the life of program.</description></item><item><title>Activity 6 - Moving the turtle</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-turtle/activity-6/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-turtle/activity-6/</guid><description>Our first step is to move the turtle to a new location to draw the flower (we don’t want to draw the flower on top of the beehive!). To do this, we first need to use the following methods:
turtle.penup() turtle.goto(x,y) turtle.pendown() turtle.penup() tells the turtle to pick up its pen so it doesn’t draw while it is moving. Then, with turtle.goto(x,y), we are telling the turtle the position where the turtle moves to.</description></item><item><title>Boolean Operators</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/csharp-guess-the-word/boolean-operators/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/csharp-guess-the-word/boolean-operators/</guid><description>Booleans Operators You can also connect boolean expressions together using the &amp;amp;&amp;amp; (AND) and the || (OR) operator. For example, suppose I ask: &amp;ldquo;Are you a human, and is Nuvi a robot?&amp;rdquo; The word &amp;ldquo;and&amp;rdquo; connects the two true-false questions together. In this case, since it is true that you are a human, and it is also true that Nuvi is a robot, then the overall result is true.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a chart that describes what happens when we connect booleans together:</description></item><item><title>Activity 5 - Use effects to fade in</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-earsketch/activity-5-use-effects-to-fade-in/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-earsketch/activity-5-use-effects-to-fade-in/</guid><description>Now that you have one effect in your song, let&amp;rsquo;s try to fade in the introduction of our song.
In activity 4, we used setEffect function to apply an effect to a specific track for the entire duration of the song, but what if you only want a specific section of your song to have an effect? Use the setEffect function with more parameters! effectStartValue: The starting value applied to the parameter effectStartLocation: The measure at which the starting value is set effectEndValue: The ending value of the parameter effectEndLocation: The measure at which the ending value is set This version of the setEffect allows for us to perform automation on a specific piece of our song.</description></item><item><title>Booleans</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/android-tictactoe/booleans/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 14:17:07 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/android-tictactoe/booleans/</guid><description>Booleans are true or false statements. Unlike strings or numbers, booleans store statements of truth: is what I am saying true or false? For example, if I ask, &amp;ldquo;Are you a robot?&amp;quot;, this question produces a true or false result, which we call a Boolean. In this case, since you are not a robot (hopefully!), we would produce false. We can also use math operators to create boolean expressions. Here are some examples; however, notice the unusual symbols for &amp;ldquo;equal to&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;not equal to&amp;rdquo;:</description></item><item><title>Activity 7 - What's wrong with the file?</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/activity-7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/activity-7/</guid><description>Malware can be dangerous! Don&amp;rsquo;t open it right away! Instead let&amp;rsquo;s use the command line to take a peek.
For files that we aren&amp;rsquo;t sure about, we need to peek at them so we don&amp;rsquo;t accidentally open a virus.
How can we look at the first lines of the file? Sometimes you just need to look at the beginning of a file. The command head shows the top of a file.</description></item><item><title>Activity 3 - Add Keyboard Input to Move the Player</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/phaser-space-invaders-game/activity-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/phaser-space-invaders-game/activity-3/</guid><description>Now, let&amp;rsquo;s allow our ship to move when the player uses the keyboard. The first step is to create a cursor attribute in the create() method in Scene2.js:
The most efficient way to create movement is to create a helper function that uses the cursor attribute to check whether the keyboard has been pressed. We have already made this function for you, and it is called movePlayer():
We then move the player with this function.</description></item><item><title>Add sound while the bird is jumping</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/jsappybird/add-jump-sound/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/jsappybird/add-jump-sound/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s add sounds to the bird while it is jumping
Add the below command in the file [File: create-game.js] jumpSound.play();
Working Together In the repl.it window below, we started the code with the line jumpSound.play();.
In your console you should see a Jsappy bird jumping with sound after you press run:</description></item><item><title>Progress Update 2</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-tensorflow/progress_update_2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 20:24:33 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-tensorflow/progress_update_2/</guid><description>Great job! You are now able to successfully identify which category an image most likely falls under.
To verify that your code is correct up to this checkpoint, please compare your code against the example code provided below.
The outputs of the code may vary. You only need to copy the code blocks, and not the output blocks, as they will be generated automatically in your notebook.
These lighter shaded blocks contain python code These darker shaded blocks contain the output</description></item><item><title>Activity 10: Making a meme!</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-pixel/activities/activity-10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-pixel/activities/activity-10/</guid><description>One other thing we can do to enhance our image is to add text. We can do that by utilizing the Pillow ImageDraw module. Let’s import that at the top of our file along with our other import statements.
from PIL import Image from PIL import ImageFilter from PIL import ImageDraw To allow us to add text, we must redraw the same image we used earlier. Let’s do that using the draw() function, which takes in an image object.</description></item><item><title>Activity 5 - The final excercise</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/web-basics/activity-5/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 17:53:41 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/web-basics/activity-5/</guid><description>Using what you&amp;rsquo;ve learned, let&amp;rsquo;s try to create a site that describes you! Try and use some or all of the following:
A heading &amp;amp; paragraph tag Different fonts Different colors Add an image to your site A list Embed a gif or video Show your style!</description></item><item><title>Wrap up</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/pygame-pong/wrapup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/pygame-pong/wrapup/</guid><description>Congratulations! You made it! We are excited to see you make it here! Hope you had fun working on your game and learning concepts that will help you make even better games
Now, it&amp;rsquo;s your turn! Use the knowledge you gained from this tutorial to make various interesting changes to the game.
Add sets to the game, where a player wins a set when they reach 21 points. The player who wins the best of 3 sets will be declared the winner.</description></item><item><title>Activity 7 - Drawing a figure 8</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-turtle/activity-7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-turtle/activity-7/</guid><description>Great! Now let’s make a figure 8 as the first step to making a mandala flower! A figure 8 is just two circles that are opposite to each other. To do this we can make use of the turtle.circle(x) method, which takes an integer x as the radius of the circle. (You may recall that 2 * radius is how wide the circle is.) Having the radius as an argument means we can decide how big or small the circle should be.</description></item><item><title>Variables</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/csharp-guess-the-word/variables/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/csharp-guess-the-word/variables/</guid><description>Variables Variables are simply names that we can give to values such as strings, numbers and booleans. We use variables to store information that the computer can keep track of.
Here&amp;rsquo;s how to declare a variable named str. We say str has the value &amp;quot;Hello World&amp;quot;. Can you describe what the other variables below mean?
var str = &amp;#34;Hello World&amp;#34;; var x = 88; var happy = true; Press run. Note that variables are not printed out to the console.</description></item><item><title>Conditionals</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/android-tictactoe/conditionals/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 14:17:07 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/android-tictactoe/conditionals/</guid><description>We can use if statements to run a code statement only if certain conditions are met.
For example:
if (isRainingOutside == true) { takeUmbrella = true; } else { takeUmbrella = false; } For our game, we should use if statements to determine if a player has 3 vertical, horizontal, or diagonal matches.
Inside the () beside if, you should specify a Boolean expression. Booleans are true or false statements. We can utilize this in our if statement.</description></item><item><title>Variables</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/android-tictactoe/variables/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 14:17:07 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/android-tictactoe/variables/</guid><description>Variables are simply names that we can give to values such as strings, numbers, and booleans. We use variables to store information so the computer can keep track of it. Variables are created by using the type of the variable and the name of the variable. Then you can assign that variable to the information that you want to store by using = and the content.
Look at the variables at the top of of MainActivity.</description></item><item><title>Activity 8 - What's different?</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/activity-8/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/activity-8/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s look at the secret message to make sure this weird malware.sh file hasn&amp;rsquo;t done anything to it!
Do we know a command that can help us find the location of the secret-message.txt file? Move into that directory and let&amp;rsquo;s check for the quote &amp;ldquo;Do. Or do not. There is no try.&amp;rdquo; from earlier. Do you remember what command can help us check?
This file usually has good and fun quotes, but there seems to be lots of changes.</description></item><item><title>Plotting the Model and its Predictions</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-tensorflow/plotting_model/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 16:19:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-tensorflow/plotting_model/</guid><description>Now that we are able to classify the category of an individual piece of clothing using your model, we will now visualize these predictions by creating a bar plot for a specified image.
Copy the following code into Colab: The plot_image function displays an image along with its predicted classification, the confidence level of the model for that category, and the actual classification (which is for reference).
The plot_value_array function plots the confidence values generated by the model as a bar graph.</description></item><item><title>Activity 11: Challenge: Make your own image</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-pixel/activities/activity-11/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-pixel/activities/activity-11/</guid><description>In this section, we will take what you have learned so far to create and change your own picture! In this section, you are free to make any combination of basic colorboards, drawing elements, filters, cropping, flipping, changing colors or text.
Challenge - Make your own image In the following repl.it, we provide you some images you can play around with. You are also welcome to add your own images.</description></item><item><title>Activity 4 - Adding Enemies</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/phaser-space-invaders-game/activity-4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/phaser-space-invaders-game/activity-4/</guid><description>Now, let’s make some enemies for our player to fight! Let’s first load a sprite sheet for our enemies in Scene 1 just like we did for the player. Use the same syntax you used to load in the player, but use a different name, 'assets/enemies.png as the source of the sprite sheet, and a frameWidth and frameHeight of 16:
In addition, create another animation in Scene 1 in the same way you created the player&amp;rsquo;s animation (you can use the same arguments for frameRate and repeat, but remember to use enemies for frames:</description></item><item><title>Bonus activities</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/jsappybird/bonus-activites/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/jsappybird/bonus-activites/</guid><description> What happens if we make gravity stronger? What happens if we make gravity have a negative value? What other wacky ways can the bird jump? How can we make him rotate quicker? What happens if we remove the 'if' around the rotation?</description></item><item><title>Hosting your website</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/web-basics/hosting/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 17:53:41 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/web-basics/hosting/</guid><description>Host your site on the internet! Now that you&amp;rsquo;ve created your own personal website, let&amp;rsquo;s host it on the internet so everyone can access it! You will need a GitHub account to do so. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have one, create one here.
Once you have created your account and verified your email address, you will land on this page.
Now, you will need to create a new repository to store the contents of your site!</description></item><item><title>Activity 8 - Creating a mandala flower</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-turtle/activity-8/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-turtle/activity-8/</guid><description>We’re done creating our first figure 8! We can now use the figure_8() function to create a mandala flower! A mandala flower is many figure 8s placed on top of each other at different angles. So, to do this we need to use a&amp;hellip; you guessed it, a loop!
Create a new function called mandala_flower(). In the loop we will call the figure_8() function we wrote earlier to create a figure 8.</description></item><item><title>Activity 3 - Declare your variables</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/csharp-guess-the-word/activity-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/csharp-guess-the-word/activity-3/</guid><description>Activity 3 This activity is split into 2 parts and will test your knowledge about variables. Before starting, look out for HINT (ACTIVITY 3) in the code, where we declare a variable called lives which stores the number of lives the player has, and use the variable to print out how many lives the player has at the start of the game. This should give you an idea for how to complete the following two parts.</description></item><item><title>Puzzle 3</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/android-tictactoe/puzzle3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 14:17:07 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/android-tictactoe/puzzle3/</guid><description>Puzzle 3a This puzzle will test your knowledge about variables. There is something strange with one of the player&amp;rsquo;s color on the board.
Find // PUZZLE 3a in the MainActivity.kt file and update the colorGreen variable to show green colored pieces on the board.
Puzzle 3b Why does Player 2 always win on the first move?! This doesn&amp;rsquo;t make any sense, solve puzzle 3b to fix the game.
Find // PUZZLE 3b in the MainActivity.</description></item><item><title>Activity 9 - Remove the Bad File</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/activity-9/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/activity-9/</guid><description>So malware.sh is definitely a bad file left by the hackers. We need to remove it and the directory holding it!
Remove the bad file! rm is a command that removes files.
The format is: rm [filenames].
rm permanently removes the file.
Remove the file we have decided is causing our problems. How can we check that the file was fully removed?
But what if we need to remove a directory?</description></item><item><title>Activity 7 - Plotting an Image's predicted Category</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-tensorflow/activity-7/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 16:19:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-tensorflow/activity-7/</guid><description>Copy and Paste the following code into Google Colab: # Grab an image from the test dataset. This shows the resolution of the image. #NOTE: This index will be changed and its corresponding plot would be displayed in the next few steps img = test_images[0] print(img.shape) # Add the image to a batch where it&amp;#39;s the only member. img = (np.expand_dims(img,0)) print(img.shape) predictions_single = probability_model.predict(img) print(predictions_single) plot_value_array(0, predictions_single[0], test_labels) #plot the graph containing all the class names _ = plt.</description></item><item><title>Activity 5 - Making the Enemies Move</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/phaser-space-invaders-game/activity-5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/phaser-space-invaders-game/activity-5/</guid><description>At the moment, the enemies are a bit boring because they’re just sitting still. Let’s make them move a little bit! Our goal will be to make them move from left to right like this: Let’s start by making the enemies move to the left once they’re created. We can do this by simply adding one line of code:
enemy.body.velocity.x = -90; Place in our createEnemies() method:
But if you test out the code now, we can see that the enemies just keep going to the left infinitely because of Phaser’s infinite canvas.</description></item><item><title>In case you were wondering</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/web-basics/conclusion/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 17:53:41 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/web-basics/conclusion/</guid><description>You might be concerned about Benji, but we are happy to tell you that he found his home through a website just like the one you are building. Benji is now a full time good boy working hard on his tricks to earn treats.</description></item><item><title>Activity 9 - Coloring your mandala flower</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-turtle/activity-9/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-turtle/activity-9/</guid><description>Now that we have the shape of a mandala flower, it’s time to color it! We’re still going to use the turtle.color() method; however this time we’re going to use an RGB value instead of a string color value, so that we can produce a larger variety of colors.
RGB (Red-Green-Blue) colors In primary school, you might recall that by mixing colors together, you can produce new colors. For example, combining red and blue together make purple.</description></item><item><title>Help, I am stuck!</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/help/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/help/</guid><description>No worries! See if any of the following helps you, if not, feel free to reach out to one of us, and we will help you. Indentation is very important when you are working in Python. Be careful of spaces &amp;amp; tabs in your code, because indentation errors can sometimes be pretty difficult to spot. However on the positive side, strict formatting makes Python code very clean and organized. Are all your variables, functions indented properly as instructed?</description></item><item><title>Reading from Console</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/csharp-guess-the-word/reading-from-console/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/csharp-guess-the-word/reading-from-console/</guid><description>Reading from Console Now that we know the basics about variables, we can now accept input from the user. Use the following line to tell the console to wait until the user types something into the console. Then, the computer takes whatever is typed into the console, and stores it into the variable called input.
var input = Console.ReadLine(); Here&amp;rsquo;s an example of how to use Console.ReadLine to accept user input:</description></item><item><title>Final Puzzle</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/android-tictactoe/finalpuzzle/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 14:17:07 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/android-tictactoe/finalpuzzle/</guid><description>Now that Player 2 is no longer automatically winning the game and all the game pieces look good, there is still one last thing that is weird. Tic-Tac-Toe rules state that a player can win when the player has 3 pieces connected horizontally, vertically, or diagonally. The game works well for detection the horizontal and vertical wins, but something is wrong with the diagonal check.
Look for // FINAL PUZZLE in the MainActivity.</description></item><item><title>Activity 10 - Let's move and replace</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/activity-10/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/activity-10/</guid><description>Great, now that the hackers&amp;rsquo; malicious file won&amp;rsquo;t cause us any more headaches, let&amp;rsquo;s restore the old file so things will run smoothly again.
How to fix the secret-message The command mv can also be used to replace the destination file with the source file.
The format is: mv [source filename] [destination name].
Replace the messed up secret message with the backup that we found earlier.
Let&amp;rsquo;s move the file into the new directory that we made.</description></item><item><title>Progress Update 3</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-tensorflow/progress_update_3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 16:19:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-tensorflow/progress_update_3/</guid><description>To verify that your code is correct up to this checkpoint, please compare your code against the example code provided below.
If you would like to test the following code, visit this link
To edit this code, click on the &amp;lsquo;Copy to Drive&amp;rsquo; button to make a personal copy of this notebook. Make sure you are logged in to your Google account.
If you are using a Nuevo Google account temporarily Once you make a copy, please make sure to replace the &amp;ldquo;Copy of&amp;rdquo; with your name, along with the file name.</description></item><item><title>Activity 6 - Restarting the Player after Being Destroyed</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/phaser-space-invaders-game/activity-6/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/phaser-space-invaders-game/activity-6/</guid><description>We have made some pretty solid enemies, but now there&amp;rsquo;s something wrong - they don&amp;rsquo;t actually do anything to you! Specifically, they can&amp;rsquo;t actually hurt you in any way. Let&amp;rsquo;s change that. In the final game, there will be two ways you can get damaged: getting shot by an enemy laser, or directly touching the enemy. Let&amp;rsquo;s start with the latter since it is a bit easier.
Collision is relatively easy in Phaser.</description></item><item><title>Activity 10 - Randomizing the color of your mandala flower petals</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-turtle/activity-10/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-turtle/activity-10/</guid><description>We’ve successfully set the color of the mandala flower to an RGB value. Now, let&amp;rsquo;s explore changing the color of the individual mandala flower petals?
We will make use of python’s random library. The random.randint() method allows us to choose a random value for each of the red, green, or blue value. To choose a value that is between 0 inclusive and 256 exclusive (in other words, between 0 and 255 inclusive), we need to use random.</description></item><item><title>Activity 4 - Putting it all together</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/csharp-guess-the-word/activity-4/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/csharp-guess-the-word/activity-4/</guid><description>Activity 4 This activity has four parts. This is a great time to use your knowledge of comments, numbers, variables, and reading from console to complete the 4 activities. Some background information for each activity is provided below, and hints are provided in the code. After each part, press run and make sure there are no errors present in the console.
Activity 4.1 First, let&amp;rsquo;s introduce some more code into our game.</description></item><item><title>Activity 11 - Store and protect files</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/activity-11/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/activity-11/</guid><description>Thanks so much for helping us fix my machine! Now let&amp;rsquo;s get everything up into one nice package.
Secure your files, so they don&amp;rsquo;t get tampered with again tar is a command that creates and extracts archived files.
An archive is a collection of archive files. An archive file holds the compressed data of one or more files.
The format is: tar [filenames].
flags Uses -c creates archive -x extracts archive -f creates archive with given filename Use tar to secure your directory of files!</description></item><item><title>Answer Key</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-tensorflow/answer_key/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 16:19:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-tensorflow/answer_key/</guid><description>Activity 1 class_names = [&amp;#39;T-shirt/top&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;Trouser&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;Pullover&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;Dress&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;Coat&amp;#39;,&amp;#39;Sandal&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;Shirt&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;Sneaker&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;Bag&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;Ankle boot&amp;#39;]
Activity 2 The max pixel value is 255 for any index used.
Activity 3 To answer Q1 you would change your code to the following:
plt.figure(figsize=(10,10)) #sets the image size to 10x10 pixels for i in range(42): #displays first 42 images with their class name plt.subplot(6,7,i+1) plt.xticks([]) plt.yticks([]) plt.grid(False) plt.imshow(train_images[i], cmap=plt.cm.binary) plt.xlabel(class_names[train_labels[i]]) plt.show() #shows images with their labels Activity 4 Answers may vary, sample answers provided below:</description></item><item><title>Activity 7 - Allowing the Player to Shoot</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/phaser-space-invaders-game/activity-7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/phaser-space-invaders-game/activity-7/</guid><description>Now, we we want to add one of the most important parts of the game - shooting the enemies! Although we can defeat enemies by crashing into them, this won&amp;rsquo;t be a good idea once we add lives later. We will create a shooting effect by creating an object for the beam using a separate JavaScript file (like we did for the explosion).
We will start with some basic stuff - loading a spritesheet and animation in Scene 1 for the player&amp;rsquo;s beams:</description></item><item><title>Activity 11 - Now, it's your turn!</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-turtle/activity-11/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-turtle/activity-11/</guid><description>If there is any time left, try drawing your own shapes and designs! Make your picture interesting using various shapes and colors.
Click here to open a new blank repl.it window to start on your creation.
Help, I am stuck! Stuck? Check the Answer key for the activity that you are stuck on!</description></item><item><title>If-else statements</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/csharp-guess-the-word/if-else-statements/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/csharp-guess-the-word/if-else-statements/</guid><description>If-else statements You can use if statements to run code statement only if certain conditions are met. Here is an example:
var myNum = (93 + 41) / 12; if (myNum == 11) { Console.WriteLine(&amp;#34;They are equal!&amp;#34;); } Inside the () beside if, you should specify a boolean expression. If the expression is true, the code inside { } is executed. In this case, since myNum is equal to 11, They are equal!</description></item><item><title>Closing</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/closing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/linux-basics/closing/</guid><description>Congratulations! You have helped us thwart the hackers evil shenanigans by learning several Linux commands and how to use them. Thanks so much for helping SHH! But don&amp;rsquo;t forget this is all Top Secret!
Click the &amp;ldquo;Download&amp;rdquo; button below to receive your honorary certificate!
Download link</description></item><item><title>Activity 8 - Allowing the Enemies to Shoot</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/phaser-space-invaders-game/activity-8/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/phaser-space-invaders-game/activity-8/</guid><description>Now, we will make the enemies shoot back at the player. Each enemy will shoot randomly, and the difficulty (which will later be escaleted with each level) is defined by how often they randomly shoot.
The enemy beam is rather similar to the player’s beam. We will again make a very similar enemyBeam.js file with nearly the same code as the playerBeam.js but with different variable names and numbers:
We will share sprite and animation for the player&amp;rsquo;s beams and enemy&amp;rsquo;s beams.</description></item><item><title>Java: TicTacToe - Answer Key</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-tictactoe/answer-key/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-tictactoe/answer-key/</guid><description>activity-1: Game SetUp public class TicTacToe_Nuevo { public static void main(String args[]){ // the board that stores moves String[] board = {&amp;#34; &amp;#34;, &amp;#34; &amp;#34;, &amp;#34; &amp;#34;, &amp;#34; &amp;#34;, &amp;#34; &amp;#34;, &amp;#34; &amp;#34;, &amp;#34; &amp;#34;, &amp;#34; &amp;#34;, &amp;#34; &amp;#34;}; // starting board that labeled position(only printed once) String[] startBoard = {&amp;#34;1&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;2&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;3&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;4&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;5&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;6&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;7&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;8&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;9&amp;#34;}; System.out.println(&amp;#34;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;~ Tic Tac Toe ~&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;\n* Choose number 1 - 9 to place your move\n* Player: &amp;#39;X&amp;#39; Computer: &amp;#39;O&amp;#39;\n&amp;#34; ); printBoard(startBoard); System.</description></item><item><title>Java: Basics - Answer Key</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-basics/answer-key/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-basics/answer-key/</guid><description>activity-1: Print Statements and Comments Hello World class Main { public static void main(String[] args) { System.out.print(&amp;#34;Hello World&amp;#34;); System.out.print(2020); System.out.print(&amp;#39;@&amp;#39;); } } Output:
Hello World2020@ Owl class Main { public static void main(String[] args) { System.out.println(&amp;#34;Hello world!&amp;#34;); System.out.println(&amp;#34; ​, ___ / ‾ ‾ ‾ ‾ ‾ ‾ ‾ ‾ ‾ ‾ ‾ ‾ ‾ ‾ ‾ ‾ ‾ ‾ \\&amp;#34;); System.out.println(&amp;#34;​`\\/{o,o} &amp;lt; Hi, I am Minerva. Patrick&amp;#39;s friend! |&amp;#34;); System.</description></item><item><title>Pygame Pong game - Answer Key</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/pygame-pong/answer-key/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 20:24:33 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/pygame-pong/answer-key/</guid><description>Activity 1 HEIGHT = 600 WIDTH = 800 Activity 2 COLOR = (70, 130, 180) Activity 3 self.paddles.append(Paddle( # The left paddle self.BALL_VELOCITY, pygame.K_w, pygame.K_s, 0, self.HEIGHT / 2 - self.PADDLE_HEIGHT / 2, self.PADDLE_WIDTH, self.PADDLE_HEIGHT )) Activity 4 self.paddles.append(Paddle( # The right paddle self.BALL_VELOCITY, pygame.K_UP, pygame.K_DOWN, self.WIDTH - self.PADDLE_WIDTH, self.HEIGHT / 2 - self.PADDLE_HEIGHT / 2, self.PADDLE_WIDTH, self.PADDLE_HEIGHT )) Activity 5 font_label = &amp;#39;arial&amp;#39; font_name = pygame.font.match_font(font_label) Activity 6 if ball.</description></item><item><title>Answer Key - Web Basics</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/web-basics/answer-key/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 12:53:41 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/web-basics/answer-key/</guid><description>Special note: This curriculum allows students to be creative. The below is just an example of what they can do, please use your best judgement and ask for guidance if needed. The answer key provided here is fairly long because we are including snippets of full HTML for context.
When a student clicks on the &amp;lsquo;Try it yourself!&amp;rsquo; it&amp;rsquo;ll open a new tab with some of the HTML code (and CSS code) already scaffolded.</description></item><item><title>Python Guess The Number - Answer Key</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-guess-number/answer-key/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 20:24:33 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-guess-number/answer-key/</guid><description>Playing with randit import random number = random.randint(1,100) print(&amp;#34;your randomly generated number is&amp;#34;, number) Create the &amp;lsquo;Guess the number game&amp;rsquo; import random #Use the random.randint() function here to generate a number #Also define the number of guesses you want to allow here randomNumber = random.randint(1,10) guessesLeft = 3 #Create a loop here that repeatedly asks the player for a number and compares it to the random number #Remember to decrease the number of guesses left so the player doesn&amp;#39;t get unlimited tries!</description></item><item><title>Python Turtle - Answer Key</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-turtle/answer-key/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 20:24:33 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-turtle/answer-key/</guid><description>The below 3 lines are needed for the introduction activity and all the other activities as well.
import turtle turtle.color(&amp;#34;orange&amp;#34;) turtle.shape(&amp;#34;turtle&amp;#34;) Introduction Activity turtle.color(&amp;#34;orange&amp;#34;) turtle.forward(50) Activity 1 turtle.forward(50) turtle.left(90) turtle.forward(50) turtle.left(90) turtle.forward(50) turtle.left(90) turtle.forward(50) turtle.left(90) Activity 2 for i in range(4): turtle.forward(50) turtle.left(90) Activity 3 for i in range(6): turtle.forward(50) turtle.left(60) Activity 4 def draw_hexagon(): for i in range(6): turtle.forward(50) turtle.left(60) draw_hexagon() Activity 5 def draw_honeycomb(): for i in range(6): draw_hexagon() turtle.</description></item><item><title>Activity 5 - Use conditional statements</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/csharp-guess-the-word/activity-5/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/csharp-guess-the-word/activity-5/</guid><description>Activity 5 This activity is split into two parts. Use your knowledge of if-else statements to complete the activities. As always, press run after completing each part to check for errors.
Activity 5.1 After the player guesses a letter, and we have checked whether the letter appears in the word, we need to check if the entire word has been guessed. If the entire word has been correctly identified, we should let the computer know that the player has won the game.</description></item><item><title>Activity 9 - Adding Score, Levels, and Lives</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/phaser-space-invaders-game/activity-9/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/phaser-space-invaders-game/activity-9/</guid><description>Now, we will add some numbers to quantify our game! The easiest one to implement is the score. Create a text variable on the top left of the screen that displays Score: and the value of a num variable that stores the player&amp;rsquo;s score.
this.scoreText = this.add.text(20, 10, &amp;#34;Score: &amp;#34; + this.score, { font: &amp;#34;25px Arial&amp;#34;, fill: &amp;#34;white&amp;#34; }); this line print score variable at the top left of the screen.</description></item><item><title>While loops</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/csharp-guess-the-word/while-loops/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/csharp-guess-the-word/while-loops/</guid><description>While loops while loops are an easy way to repeat the execution of lines without having to reuse a line many times. For example, to print Hello World five times in a row, you can do:
var counter = 1; while (counter &amp;lt;= 5) { Console.WriteLine(&amp;#34;Hello World&amp;#34;); counter = counter + 1; } Like an if statement, inside the () beside while, you should specify a boolean expression. If the expression is true, the code inside the curly braces { } is executed.</description></item><item><title>Activity 10 - Adding a Title Screen</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/phaser-space-invaders-game/activity-10/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/phaser-space-invaders-game/activity-10/</guid><description>Now, we will put our separation of scene 1 and scene 2 to good use by adding a title screen to finish off our game!
This is very simple! we will first comment out startGame() line from the bottum of create() in Scene 1. We are going to use startGame() fuction to start game instead of start automatically as before:
The console will go back to a black canvas. To make a title screen, we need to import the background screen and some text in start page section from scene 1:</description></item><item><title>Activity 6 - Complete the game!</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/csharp-guess-the-word/activity-6/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/csharp-guess-the-word/activity-6/</guid><description>Instructions Now, let&amp;rsquo;s finally address the bug that was introduced in Activity 4.2. The game should continue to ask the player to guess letters if they have some lives remaining, and they have not yet won the game. Look at the for loop. As you might have noticed, even though you might have lives remaining, the game abruptly stops after only 3 guesses. We will replace this for-loop with a while-loop, with the correct looping condition.</description></item><item><title>Answer Key - Python Image Manipulation</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/image-manipulation/answer-key/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 10:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/image-manipulation/answer-key/</guid><description>Python Basic Answers: Activity 1: # The sentences can be anything! Encourage having fun with it. print(&amp;#34;My name is Nuvi!&amp;#34;) print(&amp;#34;I love making memes.&amp;#34;) Activity 2: # There can be a variety of answers, here are a few: print(&amp;#34;Nuevo&amp;#34; + &amp;#34;&amp;#34; + &amp;#34;Foundation&amp;#34;) print(&amp;#34;Nu&amp;#34; + &amp;#34;evo&amp;#34; + &amp;#34;Found&amp;#34; + &amp;#34;ation&amp;#34;) print(&amp;#34;N&amp;#34; + &amp;#34;uevo F&amp;#34; + &amp;#34;oundation&amp;#34;) Activity 3: print(2-19) # -17 print((3 + 5) * 6) # 48 print((13 + 5 * 8) / (6 - (3 + 7))) # -13.</description></item><item><title>Answer Key - C# Guess the Word</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/csharp-guess-the-word/answer-key/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 10:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/csharp-guess-the-word/answer-key/</guid><description>Activity 1: using System; class MainClass { public static void Main(string[] args) { Console.WriteLine(&amp;#34;Hello there&amp;#34;); Console.WriteLine(&amp;#34;I am awesome&amp;#34;); } } Activity 2: using System; class MainClass { public static void Main(string[] args) { Console.WriteLine(&amp;#34;Nuevo&amp;#34; + &amp;#34; &amp;#34; + &amp;#34;Foundation&amp;#34;); Console.WriteLine(&amp;#34;Nue&amp;#34; + &amp;#34;vo &amp;#34; + &amp;#34;Foundation&amp;#34;); Console.WriteLine(&amp;#34;Nuevo &amp;#34; + &amp;#34;Foun&amp;#34; + &amp;#34;dation&amp;#34;); } } Activity 3: class MainClass { public static void Main(string[] args) { Console.WriteLine(2-19); Console.WriteLine((3+5)*6); Console.WriteLine((13+5*8)/(6-(3+7))); } } Activity 4: class MainClass { public static void Main(string[] args) { Console.</description></item><item><title>Answer Key - Phaser Space Invaders Game</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/phaser-space-invaders-game/answer-key/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 10:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/phaser-space-invaders-game/answer-key/</guid><description>Activity 1 Scene1.js
preload(){ this.load.image(&amp;#34;background&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;assets/space.png&amp;#34;); this.load.spritesheet(&amp;#39;player&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;assets/player.png&amp;#39;, { frameWidth: 32, frameHeight: 48 }); } Scene2.js
create(){ this.background = this.add.image(config.width/2, config.height/2, &amp;#34;background&amp;#34;); this.player = this.physics.add.sprite(config.width / 2, config.height - 75, &amp;#34;player&amp;#34;); } Activity 2 Scene1.js
create(){ this.anims.create({ key: &amp;#34;player_anim&amp;#34;, frames: this.anims.generateFrameNumbers(&amp;#34;player&amp;#34;), frameRate: 20, repeat: -1 }); } Scene2.js
create(){ // delete your previous background code and create it again as a tile sprite this.background = this.add.tileSprite(0, 0, config.width, config.height, &amp;#34;background&amp;#34;); this.</description></item><item><title>Project Overview</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/image-manipulation/project-overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/image-manipulation/project-overview/</guid><description>Applications like Instagram and Snapchat allow its users to modify their images. For example, you can rotate your image and make it black and white. Ever wondered how these apps do it? The answer is using code!
Today, we’re going to learn how to do some image manipulations using Python!
Setting up the project To get started let’s start with importing a module. What does that mean? To do fun stuff with images, we need to unlock some functions to use.</description></item><item><title>Open an image</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/image-manipulation/open-image/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/image-manipulation/open-image/</guid><description>To change an image, we must open an image. We can use the Pillow Image module we just imported in the setup. Let’s first find some images to open. Find an image of your choice and download it. Once you have downloaded it, navigate back to your repl.it window and upload your image by clicking on the three dots and selecting ‘upload file’.
For example, to upload the cat.jpg file:</description></item><item><title>Rotate the image</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/image-manipulation/rotate-image/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/image-manipulation/rotate-image/</guid><description>Now that we have the image in our code, let’s turn it in different directions. To do that, let’s look at the Pillow Image function rotate().
The rotate image works using angles. For example, rotate(45) will tilt your picture sideways by 45 degrees. Using rotate(90) will turn your picture sideways.
Let’s give that a try! Let’s rotate the image before we save it:
image = Image.open("cat.jpg") image.rotate(90) image.save("myCat.jpg") Hmm, the picture didn’t seem to rotate.</description></item><item><title>Image Filters</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/image-manipulation/image-filters/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/image-manipulation/image-filters/</guid><description>I want to turn my cat black and white! Let&amp;rsquo;s do this by using the Pillow ImageFilter function filter() &amp;amp; convert().
To use the filter() function, you can specify the ImageFilter type within the parentheses. For example, image.filter(ImageFilter.BLUR) will make the image blurry. Or, if you use ImageFilter.CONTOUR instead, it will add a ‘sketch’ type effect to your image.
Add something like this below your previously added code
blurredImage = image.</description></item><item><title>Making a meme!</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/image-manipulation/making-meme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/image-manipulation/making-meme/</guid><description>So now that my image looks how I want it to look, I want to add some text. We can do that by utilizing the Pillow ImageDraw module. Let’s import that at the top of our file along with our other import statements.
from PIL import Image from PIL import ImageFilter from PIL import ImageDraw To allow us to add text, we must redraw the same image we used earlier for image manipulation.</description></item><item><title>SQL Workshop Answer Key</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/sql_workshop/answer-key/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 10:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/sql_workshop/answer-key/</guid><description>Note: Do not use Firefox Browser for this workshop!
For Drag and Drop Activities: Correctly chosen blocks will have a green highlight around them while incorrect blocks will highlight in red until the player moves the block.
For Type-In Activities: Correct words/commands will be highlighted in green in the Previous Command Box, incorrectly placed or misused words will be highlighted in red. If the command players write matches the answer key and it still highlights in red, make sure there are no extra spaces at the end or beginning of the command!</description></item><item><title>Answer key - Python-Pixel</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-pixel/answer-key/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-pixel/answer-key/</guid><description>Activity1 This is the sample answer for creating a blue color board with width 100 and height 100.
from PIL import Image width=100 height=100 color=&amp;#39;blue&amp;#39; img = Image.new(&amp;#39;RGB&amp;#39;, (width, height), color) img.save(&amp;#39;pixel-activity1.png&amp;#39;) Activity2 This is the sample answer to draw a line from the middle of the color board from Activity1 to its bottom right corner.
#Create your color board from PIL import Image # setup image first img = Image.</description></item></channel></rss>