<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>KC7: Cyber Defender Game on Nuevo Foundation Workshops</title>
    <link>/kusto-kc7/</link>
    <description>Recent content in KC7: Cyber Defender Game on Nuevo Foundation Workshops</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="/kusto-kc7/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Activity 1: Login &amp; Setup of the Cyber Environment</title>
      <link>/kusto-kc7/activity-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/kusto-kc7/activity-1/</guid>
      <description>Getting Started Okay Cyber Defenders! The first thing you need to do is set up the environment in which you will be hunting hackers. In order to do that, open the links below and follow the directions on first setting up Azure Data Explorer (ADX) and then logging into the Scoreboard session.
Setting Up Azure Data Explorer (ADX) ADX is the primary tool used by some cyber defenders for data exploration and analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 1: Intro to Threat Intelligence</title>
      <link>/kusto-kc7/tutorial-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/kusto-kc7/tutorial-1/</guid>
      <description>As you step through this workshop, you&amp;rsquo;ll notice that each page with a video duplicates the lesson in both video and written form. You can follow one or the other depending on what type of learner you are.
What is Threat Intelligence? Threat Intelligence Analysts:
Learn about adversaries &amp;hellip; and share knowledge with public/private sector partners
Track adversaries over time &amp;hellip; to understand the changing threat landscape
Implement defenses &amp;hellip; and work with product development teams to protect customers</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Activity 2: Threat Intel Game</title>
      <link>/kusto-kc7/activity-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/kusto-kc7/activity-2/</guid>
      <description>Best way to complete this section is to play the video while following along with the page belowWhat is Attribution? One key topic in the world of cybersecurity you&amp;rsquo;ll come across is called attribution. Attribution in cybersecurity refers to the process of tracking, identifying, and generally attributing blame on the perpetrator of a cyber attack. Cyber attacks, also known commonly as hacking, are an attempt by an adversary to gain access to systems for the purpose of altering, stealing, destroying, or exposing information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 2: New Employee Orientation</title>
      <link>/kusto-kc7/tutorial-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/kusto-kc7/tutorial-2/</guid>
      <description>DISCLAIMER: All domains, data, and names used in this document, website, or any other materials are fictitious ... (cont.)DISCLAIMER: All domains, data, and names used in this document, website, or any other materials are fictitious and have been created solely for illustrative and educational purposes. They do not represent any real individuals, companies, or organizations.
This document, website, or any other materials, including but not limited to texts, images, graphics, logos, and software, are provided &amp;ldquo;as is&amp;rdquo; without warranty of any kind, either express or implied, including but not limited to the implied warranties of merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Activity 3: Kusto Query Language 101</title>
      <link>/kusto-kc7/activity-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/kusto-kc7/activity-3/</guid>
      <description>This is where we want you to pull up the Scoreboard and ADX viewer from earlier in separate windows to complete the remaining exercises. If you can&amp;rsquo;t or don&amp;rsquo;t want to use the Scoreboard, all questions for this section are listed below.
Remember any page with a video duplicates the lesson in both video and written form. You can follow one or the other depending on what type of learner you are.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Activity 3.5: KQL 101 Answers Explained</title>
      <link>/kusto-kc7/activity-3_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/kusto-kc7/activity-3_5/</guid>
      <description>View the video above for a walkthrough of how to get to the answers for the last section. If you feel like you have a good grasp on most of the answers (i.e. greened up your KQL 101 Scoreboard) then feel free to move on to the next section or skip through this video for specific answers.
Whew! I know that was a lot at once, but don&amp;rsquo;t worry you will get more time to explore the data to help you digest this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Activity 4: Catch the Hacker</title>
      <link>/kusto-kc7/activity-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/kusto-kc7/activity-4/</guid>
      <description>This is a much shorter section, we&amp;rsquo;re just going to explain the scenario and let you go for free hunting time. You can take however much time you&amp;rsquo;d like to on this portion, but for live sessions we generally give participants 30-40 minutes before moving on.
Be sure you use the SecurityLogs database Submit your answers &amp;ldquo;Introducing the Hackers&amp;rdquo; challenge on the Scoreboard Happy Hunting! Introducing the Hackers Now that you’ve completed your initial round of training, you are ready to work your first case in the SOC!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Activity 4.5: Catch the Hacker Answers Explained</title>
      <link>/kusto-kc7/activity-4_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/kusto-kc7/activity-4_5/</guid>
      <description>View the video above for a walkthrough of how to get to the answers for the last section.
Congrats on making it through your initial Cyber Defender training!
If you&amp;rsquo;re hungry for more, we have a few bonus activities here for you to try out. Keep in mind that the Scoreboard for these bonus activities will give some hints and show you when an answer is correct, however we will NOT publish an answer key for these, it&amp;rsquo;s up to you to reveil the correct answers yourselves in the Scoreboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bonus 1: Phishy Activity</title>
      <link>/kusto-kc7/activity-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/kusto-kc7/activity-5/</guid>
      <description>Hackers Sending Malware Docs After digging for a bit on the phishing activity, you come across another tweet from a threat intelligence vendor SolitaryStrike:
🤔 Use the tweet to begin your hunt. Let the questions help you pivot through the data to figure out what&amp;rsquo;s going on.
Submit your answers to the &amp;ldquo;Hackers Sending0 Malware Docs&amp;rdquo; challenge on the Scoreboard at https://kc7cyber.azurewebsites.net/to get feedback and earn points. Questions below are reflected in the Scoreboard for this section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bonus 2: Truth or Misinformation?</title>
      <link>/kusto-kc7/activity-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/kusto-kc7/activity-6/</guid>
      <description>Cyber Blog Analysis For this scenario, we&amp;rsquo;d like you to take a look at the blog post below and see if you can find evidence in SecurityLogs2 that supports or disproves the information posted.
[Start Blog Post]
What is UnhelpfulDesk?
UnhelpfulDesk malware implants are dropped by files with names that resemble legitimate IT functions, such as software updates or password resets, or medical research topics, such as vaccine research. These files are delivered to victims via malicious emails containing links to download the files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bonus 3: Security Jeopardy</title>
      <link>/kusto-kc7/activity-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/kusto-kc7/activity-7/</guid>
      <description>via GIPHY
Let&amp;rsquo;s Play a Round of Jeopardy! Greetings Cyber Defenders!
For those of you still here and eager for more points to bring up your Scoreboard total, we have just the game for you. On the Scoreboard, you have likely noticed one last challenge titled &amp;ldquo;Security Jeopardy&amp;rdquo;. This is a quiz we made to help you learn about more terms and concepts related to cybersecurity. If you are interested in a career in cybersecurity, if you&amp;rsquo;re feeling curious about how to be more security minded while using technology, or if that part of your brain is just telling you to green up as many questions as possible to max out your game score &amp;hellip; you are going to like this one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>T3: Train-the-Trainer Intro</title>
      <link>/kusto-kc7/trainer-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/kusto-kc7/trainer-1/</guid>
      <description>Welcome New Trainers! First off, we are excited that you have decided to join us in our goal to make cybersecurity more diverse. Thank you for helping us with our goal of making cybersecurity more accessible by putting KC7 within reach of every high school and university student in the world! - KC7 Architects Simeon Kakpovi, Greg Schloemer, &amp;amp; Emily Hacker
[Check out our interview on the SANS podcast.]
Know Your Why In order to effectively teach this course, it is important for you to know your why.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>T3: Choosing the Right Event Style</title>
      <link>/kusto-kc7/trainer-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/kusto-kc7/trainer-2/</guid>
      <description>How It Works Eample Scenario Choosing the right event for you Audiences There are several audiences that can benefit from playing KC7. You should first identify your intended audience, then adjust how you configure the game to make sure they get the most out of it.
Audience Goal Needs/Benefits Middle and High School Students Get excited No experience with cybersecurity. You can use KC7 to give them excited about cybersecurity and get them exposure to the field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>T3: Event Schedule &amp; Logistics</title>
      <link>/kusto-kc7/trainer-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/kusto-kc7/trainer-3/</guid>
      <description>Schedule [PREREQ, 10 min] Gain access to cluster and add it to ADX
Part 1: Understanding the Environment [1.5 hrs] [5 min] Intro to Threat Intel - Briefly mention attribution tools and techniques - Diamond Model - Kill Chain
[20 min] Kusto Query Language (KQL) 101 - Introduce tables, commands, and syntax for KQL in ADX browser - where (has, contains, has_any, ==, etc…) - count - take - let</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
