<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Arrays on Nuevo Foundation Workshops</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/javascript-basics/arrays/</link><description>Recent content in Arrays on Nuevo Foundation Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 11:45:38 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/javascript-basics/arrays/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Properties</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/javascript-basics/arrays/properties/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/javascript-basics/arrays/properties/</guid><description>Array properties or characteristics are a way to describe the attributes of the array. Examples include: the total number of elements, the value at a particular index, etc&amp;hellip;
Here is a list of the properties of the Array object along with their description.
Constructor() Returns a reference to the array function that created the object.
Syntax:
arrayName.constructor; Example: Index() The property represents the zero-based index of the match in the string.</description></item><item><title>Iterating over Arrays</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/javascript-basics/arrays/iteration/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/javascript-basics/arrays/iteration/</guid><description>One of the common array operations is to iterate over the values and process each one of them in some way. Let&amp;rsquo;s go over and discuss some of the simplest ways to achieve this:
Array.forEach() The forEach() method calls a function (a callback function. In this case, function named printBr) once for each array element.
The function passed to forEach is executed once for every item in the array, with the array item passed as the argument to the function.</description></item><item><title>Methods</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/javascript-basics/arrays/methods/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/javascript-basics/arrays/methods/</guid><description>Methods represent some action we wish to perform on the array. They can be used to change the behaviour or perform some operations on itself.
To make things easier, arrays provide a lot of methods. Let&amp;rsquo;s go over some of the basic ones which would give you an idea of they look like.
How is it different compared to properties ? Properties are basically information that an array has. Methods are what an array can do.</description></item></channel></rss>