<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Conditional statements and loops on Nuevo Foundation Workshops</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/conditional-statements-loops/</link><description>Recent content in Conditional statements and loops on Nuevo Foundation Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/conditional-statements-loops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Conditional statements</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/conditional-statements-loops/conditional-statements/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/conditional-statements-loops/conditional-statements/</guid><description>Now that we know the basics of print statements, variables, and reading in input from the user – we can combine all these awesome skills with conditional statements. Conditional statements allow the computer to make decisions based off the value of an expression. In the real world, we use conditional statements all the time to make decisions! For example, if it is raining outside, then I use an umbrella. In this example, the I evaluated the weather outside and because it was raining, I made the sequential decision to use an umbrella.</description></item><item><title>Else-if Condition</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/conditional-statements-loops/else-if-statement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/conditional-statements-loops/else-if-statement/</guid><description>We have already learned some basic if-else conditions from previous workshops, click on the link below if you want to review.
Conditional statements We will introduce a new condition called &amp;ldquo;elif&amp;rdquo;.
Elif Condition Elif Keyword represents the &amp;ldquo;else-if&amp;rdquo; condition. It is used when you want to have if the last if condition is not true, try this condition.
# This is my first line of code if expression: statement(s) elif expression: statement(s) else: statement(s) Let&amp;rsquo;s see an example # This is an example if 1 &amp;gt; 3: print(&amp;#39;1&amp;gt;3&amp;#39;) elif 1 == 3: print(&amp;#39;1=3&amp;#39;) else: print(&amp;#39;1&amp;lt;3&amp;#39;) Since we can see that 1 greater than 3 is false, so it evaluates to false.</description></item><item><title>Loops</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/conditional-statements-loops/loops/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/conditional-statements-loops/loops/</guid><description>Loops in Python If you want to repeat a task multiple times, Python has a way to do that easily using loops. There are two types of basic loops in python: for loops and while loops.
For loops For loops iterate over a sequence. Let&amp;rsquo;s say you wanted to repeat a simple task 5 times. Here is how you would do it.
The following for loop iterates through each of the numbers in the list [1,2,3,4,5], and assigns the value x to it.</description></item><item><title>Nested loops</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/conditional-statements-loops/nested-loops/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/conditional-statements-loops/nested-loops/</guid><description>Nested loops To learn nested loops, you need to know simple for-loops and while loops. If you have already learnt them, you can skip to the next part. Otherwise, jump to a specific Python section to learn more about these topics:
For-loop and While-loop In this section, we will use one loop inside another, which is called nested loop. Nested while loop #This is the format for nested while loop while expressionA: while expressionB: statement(B) statement(A) In the while loop above, when expressionA produces False, we will skip the whole block.</description></item></channel></rss>