<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Spy Game on Nuevo Foundation Workshops</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security/</link><description>Recent content in Spy Game on Nuevo Foundation Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Meeting Alice, Bob and Eve</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security/meeting-alice-bob-eve/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security/meeting-alice-bob-eve/</guid><description>Meet our friend Bob. Bob has a secret that he doesn’t want to share, he would like to keep it secured. He has the secret locked somewhere safe. Only Bob has the key to the lock to make sure that no one can get to his secret but him.
Meet our not so good friend Eve. Eve wants access to Bob’s secret.
Eve realizes that to get to Bob&amp;lsquo;s secret, they need to first get past Bob&amp;lsquo;s lock.</description></item><item><title>Password Basics</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security/password-basics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security/password-basics/</guid><description>Our Secret Agent Alice solves the case by explaining Bob about Passwords!!!
What is a Password? Passwords are the key to the lock to your virtual world. Just like your secret is kept safe in a secure room using a lock and a key similarly your personal information on the internet is secured by your login password and username. The secure room is only as secure as the key to the lock on the door.</description></item><item><title>Activity</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security/activity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security/activity/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s play a game!
Write your favorite sentence in the text box below. Make sure it has at least five words. (E.g. I like playing volleyball at the beach.) Now take the first letter of each word from the above sentence and write inside the text box. (E.g. ilpvatb) Add some numbers to the text. Remember the position of the numbers. (E.g. 1ilpvatb6) Finally, let's add some special characters to the text.</description></item><item><title>Spy Game</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security/spy-game/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security/spy-game/</guid><description>From our last activity we learnt that a strong password is a combination of random characters (possibly having uppercase and lowercase letters), numbers and some special characters. Now it&amp;rsquo;s time to play Hacked or Safe!
From a list of passwords used by our Nuvi select the strongest password which cannot be hacked by Eve.
Can this password be Hacked? Yes No Can this password be Hacked? Yes No Can this password be Hacked?</description></item><item><title>Summary</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security/summary/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security/summary/</guid><description>Remember the characteristics of a strong password are: At least 8 characters - the more characters, the better A mixture of letters and numbers Inclusion of at least one special character, e.g., ! @ # ? ] Note: do not use &amp;lt; or &amp;gt; in your password, as both can cause problems in Web browsers A strong password is hard to guess, but it should be easy for you to remember - a password that has to be written down is not strong, no matter how many of the above characteristics are employed.</description></item><item><title>Answer Key - Security</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security/answer-key/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security/answer-key/</guid><description>Solution In our Spy Game the passwords &amp;ldquo;Ilovemypet&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;12345678&amp;rdquo; are weak and can be easily hacked/guessed by a malicious person.</description></item></channel></rss>