<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Python: Image Manipulation on Nuevo Foundation Workshops</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/image-manipulation/</link><description>Recent content in Python: Image Manipulation on Nuevo Foundation Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 13:24:17 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/image-manipulation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Answer Key - Python Image Manipulation</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/image-manipulation/answer-key/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 10:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/image-manipulation/answer-key/</guid><description>Python Basic Answers: Activity 1: # The sentences can be anything! Encourage having fun with it. print(&amp;#34;My name is Nuvi!&amp;#34;) print(&amp;#34;I love making memes.&amp;#34;) Activity 2: # There can be a variety of answers, here are a few: print(&amp;#34;Nuevo&amp;#34; + &amp;#34;&amp;#34; + &amp;#34;Foundation&amp;#34;) print(&amp;#34;Nu&amp;#34; + &amp;#34;evo&amp;#34; + &amp;#34;Found&amp;#34; + &amp;#34;ation&amp;#34;) print(&amp;#34;N&amp;#34; + &amp;#34;uevo F&amp;#34; + &amp;#34;oundation&amp;#34;) Activity 3: print(2-19) # -17 print((3 + 5) * 6) # 48 print((13 + 5 * 8) / (6 - (3 + 7))) # -13.</description></item><item><title>Project Overview</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/image-manipulation/project-overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/image-manipulation/project-overview/</guid><description>Applications like Instagram and Snapchat allow its users to modify their images. For example, you can rotate your image and make it black and white. Ever wondered how these apps do it? The answer is using code!
Today, we’re going to learn how to do some image manipulations using Python!
Setting up the project To get started let’s start with importing a module. What does that mean? To do fun stuff with images, we need to unlock some functions to use.</description></item><item><title>Open an image</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/image-manipulation/open-image/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/image-manipulation/open-image/</guid><description>To change an image, we must open an image. We can use the Pillow Image module we just imported in the setup. Let’s first find some images to open. Find an image of your choice and download it. You can also use the one we use in this workshop: Click to download.
Once you have downloaded it, navigate back to your repl.it window and upload your image by clicking on the three dots and selecting ‘upload file’.</description></item><item><title>Rotate the image</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/image-manipulation/rotate-image/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/image-manipulation/rotate-image/</guid><description>Now that we have the image in our code, let’s turn it in different directions. To do that, let’s look at the Pillow Image function rotate().
The rotate image works using angles. For example, rotate(45) will tilt your picture sideways by 45 degrees. Using rotate(90) will turn your picture sideways.
Let’s give that a try! Let’s rotate the image before we save it:
image = Image.open(&amp;#34;cat.jpg&amp;#34;) image.rotate(90) image.save(&amp;#34;myCat.jpg&amp;#34;) Hmm, the picture didn’t seem to rotate.</description></item><item><title>Image Filters</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/image-manipulation/image-filters/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/image-manipulation/image-filters/</guid><description>I want to turn my cat black and white! Let&amp;rsquo;s do this by using the Pillow ImageFilter function filter() &amp;amp; convert().
To use the filter() function, you can specify the ImageFilter type within the parentheses. For example, image.filter(ImageFilter.BLUR) will make the image blurry. Or, if you use ImageFilter.CONTOUR instead, it will add a ‘sketch’ type effect to your image.
Add something like this below your previously added code
blurredImage = image.</description></item><item><title>Making a meme!</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/image-manipulation/making-meme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/image-manipulation/making-meme/</guid><description>So now that my image looks how I want it to look, I want to add some text. We can do that by utilizing the Pillow ImageDraw module. Let’s import that at the top of our file along with our other import statements.
from PIL import Image from PIL import ImageFilter from PIL import ImageDraw To allow us to add text, we must redraw the same image we used earlier for image manipulation.</description></item></channel></rss>