<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Security: Gone Phishing on Nuevo Foundation Workshops</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security-phishing/</link><description>Recent content in Security: Gone Phishing on Nuevo Foundation Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security-phishing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bob goes fishing</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security-phishing/bob-goes-fishing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security-phishing/bob-goes-fishing/</guid><description>Meet our friend Bob. Bob is a nice and jolly gentleman. His hobbies are travelling and fishing. One fine evening Bob received an email saying he won a free trip to the &amp;ldquo;Bahamas&amp;rdquo;. Bob got excited. He immediately clicked the link to enter his personal details and waited for his itinerary to come.
Bob decided to go shopping for his trip. He bought new clothes and a new fishing rod. However, 24 hours later, he still didn&amp;rsquo;t receive a confirmation for his trip.</description></item><item><title>Phishing Basics</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security-phishing/phishing-basics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security-phishing/phishing-basics/</guid><description>Our Secret Agent Alice explains to Bob about Phishing!!!
What is Phishing? Just like when fishing, one uses a bait to catch fish on a rod, malicious hackers use different types of bait to steal personal information from unsuspecting people.
Phishing is a type of social engineering attack which is used to steal sensitive data, including login credentials, banking and credit card details. It occurs when a Hacker, posing as a trusted entity, lures an individual using email, text message, or phone.</description></item><item><title>A closer look</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security-phishing/a-closer-look/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security-phishing/a-closer-look/</guid><description>Bob received the following email the other night.
What do you think is suspicious here? Let&amp;rsquo;s analyze the email: The sender's email address is suspicious and you don't know this email sender personally.
Lucrative offer in the subject line suggests it's too good to be true.
You received an email during irregular business hours.
These words show a sense of urgency.
The sender is asking you to click on a link or open an attachment that you don't know about.</description></item><item><title>More about phishing</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security-phishing/other-phishing-types/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security-phishing/other-phishing-types/</guid><description>Alice goes on to explain different kinds of phishing scams other than the email phishing.
Smishing (SMS Phishing) Phishing conducted via Short Message Service (SMS), a telephone-based text messaging service. A smishing text, for example, attempts to entice a victim into revealing personal information via a link that leads to a phishing website. In the above image, an unknown sender texts you about free deals on iPads and lures you into clicking a malicious link.</description></item><item><title>What's Phishy?</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security-phishing/whats-phishy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security-phishing/whats-phishy/</guid><description>From our last section we learned about different types of phishing methods and how to recognize them. Now it&amp;rsquo;s time to play a game called What's phishy?
From a list of images given below choose whether you think it&amp;rsquo;s phishy or not?
Does this email look phishy? Yes No Does this email look phishy? Yes No -- Does this banner look phishy? Yes No Does this text message look phishy?</description></item><item><title>Summary</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security-phishing/summary/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/security-phishing/summary/</guid><description>Conclusion In conclusion, the common features found in Phishing scams have at least one of the following properties:
Lucrative offers or attention grabbing statements. Unusual sender of unexpected behavior or character. Sense of urgency by asking you to act fast because of limited time offers or deals. Example: Your password is about to expire click here to change it immediately. Suspicious hyperlinks. Hovering over the link will show the actual URL you will be directed to.</description></item></channel></rss>