<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Introduction to Data Structures on Nuevo Foundation Workshops</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-datastructures/introduction/</link><description>Recent content in Introduction to Data Structures on Nuevo Foundation Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 13:24:17 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-datastructures/introduction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Setting Up</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-datastructures/introduction/setting-up/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-datastructures/introduction/setting-up/</guid><description>-- Setting Up Repl.it! In this workshop, you will be using Replit to learn how to code in Java. Here is an example interactive window that you will use today:
Before we start, let&amp;rsquo;s first understand how the Replit works. The main.java file contains code, or instructions for the computer to run. By pressing the run button, you tell the computer to perform the instructions in the code. Any results from running the code will be displayed on the bottom white screen, under the result tab.</description></item><item><title>Prerequisites</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-datastructures/introduction/prerequisites/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-datastructures/introduction/prerequisites/</guid><description>-- Variables Before you start this workshop, you should have some prior knowledge of how Java variables work and how you can create them. Click here to review the Java Basics workshop! Don&amp;rsquo;t worry if you still feel a little shaky! We&amp;rsquo;ll slowly introduce you to these topics at hand. However, if you have no idea what variables are, we strongly recommend you to go ahead and finish the java basics workshop beforehand.</description></item><item><title>For Loops</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-datastructures/introduction/for-loops/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-datastructures/introduction/for-loops/</guid><description>-- When you know exactly how many times you want to loop through a block of code, use a for loop instead of a while loop:
for (initialization; condition; iteration) { // code block to be executed } initialization is executed (one time) before the execution of the code block. condition (as the name implies) defines the condition for executing the code block. iteration is executed (every time) after the code block has been executed.</description></item></channel></rss>