<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Python: Building a Pong Game on Nuevo Foundation Workshops</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/pygame-pong/</link><description>Recent content in Python: Building a Pong Game on Nuevo Foundation Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 13:24:17 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/pygame-pong/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using Repl.It</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/pygame-pong/using-repl-it/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/pygame-pong/using-repl-it/</guid><description>To build our game, we will use the Pygame library, which provides a set of readymade functionality that we can use to build Pong and its animations.
Using Repl.it Today, you will be using Repl.it to build the Pong game.
If you would like a re-cap on how to use Repl.it, check out the following Python basics tutorial
Next, let&amp;rsquo;s explain further some of the code that has been provided to you in the main.</description></item><item><title>The Basics - Class and Object</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/pygame-pong/the-basics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/pygame-pong/the-basics/</guid><description>Classes and objects Before you start building a game, you should know how to draw different objects and modify them as per the way they need to look and move on computer screen.
In order to build objects, you first decide how they should look, what role they should perform in your game, and how player can control their movement on screen. You do this by creating a class for each object you want on screen.</description></item><item><title>Activity 1 - Define the width of the Pong screen</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/pygame-pong/activity-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/pygame-pong/activity-1/</guid><description>Activity 1 You can adjust the boundary of the Pong game by adjusting the height and width of the rectangle that represents the boundary.
Go to the code containing the Pong game. Press run. Notice that the game&amp;rsquo;s boundary doesn&amp;rsquo;t look right - see the image below. Let&amp;rsquo;s fix this in this activity, so the game boundary looks good.
Find // TODO (ACTIVITY 1) in the code. Modify the WIDTH attribute of Pong class.</description></item><item><title>Activity 2 - Change the color of objects in game.</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/pygame-pong/activity-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/pygame-pong/activity-2/</guid><description>Activity 2 Great! You just fixed the game&amp;rsquo;s boundary. Now, notice how everything inside the game looks black and white. Let&amp;rsquo;s give it some colors.
To do this, we need to modify the RGB values in COLOR attribute. RGB stands for RED, GREEN, BLUE. In a computer screen, you can modify the color of each pixel by modifying its RGB value. Every color can be represented by combination of different RGB values in it.</description></item><item><title>Activity 3 - Change the key assignment to move left paddle</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/pygame-pong/activity-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/pygame-pong/activity-3/</guid><description>Activity 3 Kudos! You not only fixed the game boundary, but you are able to give color to objects too. Now, let&amp;rsquo;s see if you can change the keys for paddle movement.
To do this, we need to modify one of the parameters we passed in when creating the left paddle object. Remember from the basics section, you defined the Paddle class with UP and DOWN key assignments as its attributes.</description></item><item><title>Activity 4 - Change the key assignment to move right paddle.</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/pygame-pong/activity-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/pygame-pong/activity-4/</guid><description>Activity 4 Now you know how to change key assignments to control a paddle&amp;rsquo;s movement. Great work!
We have added movement for the left paddle. Can you apply the knowledge about the Paddle object and its attributes that influence its movement on screen to change the key assignment for the right paddle?
Find // TODO (ACTIVITY 4) in the code. Modify the appropriate attribute value for the right paddle such that pressing the 'UP' key moves the right paddle up.</description></item><item><title>Activity 5 - Declare and use a variable for font</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/pygame-pong/activity-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/pygame-pong/activity-5/</guid><description>Activity 5 Great progress so far! Now let&amp;rsquo;s make use of a variable to change the font of the text in the game.
In this activity, you need to apply the knowledge about variables you learned in Python basics.
Find // TODO (ACTIVITY 5) in the code. Declare the variable font_label, assign it the value 'arial'. Now take a look at this statement in the code font_name = pygame.font.match_font('arial'). Can you figure out the place in this statement where you should use this new variable to control the font displayed on screen?</description></item><item><title>Activity 6 - Fix the 'if' condition to track correct score.</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/pygame-pong/activity-6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/pygame-pong/activity-6/</guid><description>Activity 6 You have come a long way; we hope you are enjoying this workshop!
In this activity, you need to apply your knowledge of &amp;lsquo;if&amp;rsquo; control structures you learned in the Python basics workshop.
Find // TODO (ACTIVITY 6) in the code. We introduced an 'if' block on purpose that has the wrong condition for tracking the score when the right paddle misses the ball. This not only causes the wrong score to be displayed on screen; it causes the ball to move in an erratic manner.</description></item><item><title>Activity 7 - Define the key combination to exit the game</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/pygame-pong/activity-7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/pygame-pong/activity-7/</guid><description>Activity 7 Time for the final activity in this workshop; yay! You have done an awesome job getting here. You should be proud of yourself!
In this activity, you need to change the way the game exits anytime a given key combination is pressed.
Find // TODO (ACTIVITY 7) in the code. The Pygame library gives you a handy way by using event to detect what keystrokes are being pressed anytime during the life of program.</description></item><item><title>Wrap up</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/pygame-pong/wrapup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/pygame-pong/wrapup/</guid><description>Congratulations! You made it! We are excited to see you make it here! Hope you had fun working on your game and learning concepts that will help you make even better games
Now, it&amp;rsquo;s your turn! Use the knowledge you gained from this tutorial to make various interesting changes to the game.
Add sets to the game, where a player wins a set when they reach 21 points. The player who wins the best of 3 sets will be declared the winner.</description></item><item><title>Pygame Pong game - Answer Key</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/pygame-pong/answer-key/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 20:24:33 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/pygame-pong/answer-key/</guid><description>Activity 1 HEIGHT = 600 WIDTH = 800 Activity 2 COLOR = (70, 130, 180) Activity 3 self.paddles.append(Paddle( # The left paddle self.BALL_VELOCITY, pygame.K_w, pygame.K_s, 0, self.HEIGHT / 2 - self.PADDLE_HEIGHT / 2, self.PADDLE_WIDTH, self.PADDLE_HEIGHT )) Activity 4 self.paddles.append(Paddle( # The right paddle self.BALL_VELOCITY, pygame.K_UP, pygame.K_DOWN, self.WIDTH - self.PADDLE_WIDTH, self.HEIGHT / 2 - self.PADDLE_HEIGHT / 2, self.PADDLE_WIDTH, self.PADDLE_HEIGHT )) Activity 5 font_label = &amp;#39;arial&amp;#39; font_name = pygame.font.match_font(font_label) Activity 6 if ball.</description></item></channel></rss>