<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Python: Create music with EarSketch on Nuevo Foundation Workshops</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-earsketch/</link><description>Recent content in Python: Create music with EarSketch on Nuevo Foundation Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 11:45:38 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-earsketch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Meet DJ Nuevo</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-earsketch/meet-dj-nuevo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-earsketch/meet-dj-nuevo/</guid><description>Nuevo has new headphones! Can you find yours? You got contacted to make Nuvi&amp;rsquo;s next hit mixtape, but when you get to the studio, Nuvi says their next project is going to be produced all in code. This is something that hasn&amp;rsquo;t been done before, are you up to the challenge? Look around yourself to find your headphones and get ready to join him!
Before we start, make sure that your headphones are working.</description></item><item><title>Music Basics</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-earsketch/music-basics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-earsketch/music-basics/</guid><description>Basics first. A few things about music. What is Music? Music is the chronological organisation of sounds; that is, making certain sounds at certain times, which make melodic, rhythmic and harmonic sense. The first, most basic concept, is keeping the sounds &amp;ldquo;in time&amp;rdquo;. This leads us to some of the first few musical concepts: beat, rhythm, duration &amp;amp; tempo.
Beat is the regular pulse which provides a timeline for the rhythm to anchor itself to.</description></item><item><title>Python Basics</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-earsketch/python-basics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-earsketch/python-basics/</guid><description>Python basics To code music, we need to learn a little Python. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, it won&amp;rsquo;t bite you. Python is one of the languages that we humans use to tell computers what to do. These languages are known as &amp;ldquo;programming languages&amp;rdquo;. We will learn Python concepts throughout the class, but let&amp;rsquo;s start with a simple print statement.
If you want to jump to a specific Python section, click on the topic below:</description></item><item><title>Getting started with Earsketch</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-earsketch/getting-started-earsketch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-earsketch/getting-started-earsketch/</guid><description>EarSketch is a free educational programming environment developed at Georgia Institute of Technology. We will be composing music using EarSketch today.
To make music, click on EarSketch to open it in a new tab.
Now, let&amp;rsquo;s get started. Click on Scripts icon on the left menu bar and select Create a new script. When prompted to enter the script name, enter myjam and click on Create button.</description></item><item><title>Activity 1 - Set tempo &amp; add sounds</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-earsketch/activity-1-set-tempo-add-sounds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-earsketch/activity-1-set-tempo-add-sounds/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s take a closer look at the pre-existing code and understand what it means. We will be placing our new code between the setTempo() and finish() functions. The setTempo() function allows you to set the overall project tempo.
Quick Fact: Tempo is the speed at which a piece of music is played. Changing a project&amp;rsquo;s tempo allows for different styles of music to be created. Try changing the tempo of your setTempo function and see what happens!</description></item><item><title>Activity 2 - Make a song!</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-earsketch/activity-2-make-a-song/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-earsketch/activity-2-make-a-song/</guid><description>Now that you have learned how to add sounds to Earsketch, let&amp;rsquo;s try and make a song! You should already have one audio clip in Earsketch, but songs are made up of various instruments, so we need to add more audio clips.
Add another fitMedia() call. Find an audio clip you would like to add to your current song and input it under the fileName parameter. The trackNumber parameter should be a unique number.</description></item><item><title>Activity 3 - Organize your song using functions</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-earsketch/activity-3-organize-songs-using-functions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-earsketch/activity-3-organize-songs-using-functions/</guid><description>In Earsketch, functions are mostly used to organize different sections of a song. The most common musical form is A-B-A where each section is four measures in length, and the A sections sound different from the B section.
Now that we learned how to use functions, let&amp;rsquo;s try to use them to organize our songs better.
Define your function with a startMeasure parameter and endMeasure parameter. Place the sounds you would like to have the function represent underneath your function definition.</description></item><item><title>Activity 4 - Add effects to your song</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-earsketch/activity-4-add-effects-to-your-songs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-earsketch/activity-4-add-effects-to-your-songs/</guid><description>Effects in EarSketch Effects allows the producer to alter the sound of the audio clip into its own unique sound. Similar to how we used fitMedia() to add new audio clips, we must use the setEffect() function to define specific effects for each audio clip. It is important to note that multiple effects can be placed on the same track. This allows for the producer to combine multiple effects together.</description></item><item><title>Activity 5 - Use effects to fade in</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-earsketch/activity-5-use-effects-to-fade-in/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-earsketch/activity-5-use-effects-to-fade-in/</guid><description>Now that you have one effect in your song, let&amp;rsquo;s try to fade in the introduction of our song.
In activity 4, we used setEffect function to apply an effect to a specific track for the entire duration of the song, but what if you only want a specific section of your song to have an effect? Use the setEffect function with more parameters! effectStartValue: The starting value applied to the parameter effectStartLocation: The measure at which the starting value is set effectEndValue: The ending value of the parameter effectEndLocation: The measure at which the ending value is set This version of the setEffect allows for us to perform automation on a specific piece of our song.</description></item></channel></rss>