<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Data Structures on Nuevo Foundation Workshops</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/data-structures/</link><description>Recent content in Data Structures on Nuevo Foundation Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/data-structures/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lists</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/data-structures/lists/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/data-structures/lists/</guid><description>Lists are the ordered collection of items and can be written as comma separated values inside square bracket []. You can access the element of a list by using indexes inside square bracket. The index starts from 0 and goes up to the (number of elements in the list - 1) and the first element is at index 0. So, a list having 6 elements will have indices from 0 to 5.</description></item><item><title>Tuples</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/data-structures/tuples/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/data-structures/tuples/</guid><description>A Tuple is also an ordered collection of elements just like lists, but tuples are immutable. So you can not change the elements of a tuple after it is assigned (unlike lists where you are allowed to do so). This immutable nature makes tuples very useful when you don&amp;rsquo;t want your data to be mutated through out the program. Along with this, tuples are generally used to store elements of different data types.</description></item><item><title>Sets</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/data-structures/sets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/python-basics/data-structures/sets/</guid><description>Just like a list, a set is a collection of items. The difference between a set and a list is that a set cannot contain duplicates. So, if you have 5 chocolates and you put them in a set, you&amp;rsquo;ll only be left with 1 chocolate as duplicates will be removed. 😢
In the image above, the left side represents Indoor Games (Chess &amp;amp; Table Tennis) while the right side represents the Outdoor Games (Cricket &amp;amp; Football).</description></item></channel></rss>