<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Arrays on Nuevo Foundation Workshops</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-datastructures/arrays/</link><description>Recent content in Arrays on Nuevo Foundation Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 13:24:17 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-datastructures/arrays/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What is an Array?</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-datastructures/arrays/introduction/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-datastructures/arrays/introduction/</guid><description>-- Arrays are a data structure where each of its elements are arranged in a numerical sequence and each item is referenced by its position number. In Java, each of these elements are of one type (String, int, double, etc.) and are zero indexed, which means that the first element in an array starts at 0, the second element with 1, and so on.
Here are some important vocabulary that you will need to know before we talk more about arrays.</description></item><item><title>Array Methods and Examples</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-datastructures/arrays/methods/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-datastructures/arrays/methods/</guid><description>-- Creating an array Arrays are used to store multiple values in a single variable, instead of declaring separate variables for each value. To declare an array, define the variable type with square brackets.
{ String[] restaurants; } We have now declared a variable that holds an array of strings. To insert values to it, we can use an array literal - place the values in a comma-separated list, inside curly braces:</description></item><item><title>Problem 1: Array basics</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-datastructures/arrays/problem-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-datastructures/arrays/problem-1/</guid><description>-- Task 1: Printing We&amp;rsquo;ve created an array of existing restaurants in our system! We need your help to print out everything so we do not include the same restaurants.
Use a for Loop to print out on repl.it below. Use the length() method to find the size of the array! Look at example below!
If we are given the array below:
String[] restaurants = { &amp;#34;Burger King&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Chipotle&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Panda Express&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;McDonalds&amp;#34; }; the answer should print out:</description></item><item><title>Problem 2: Advanced Arrays</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-datastructures/arrays/problem-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-datastructures/arrays/problem-2/</guid><description>-- Task 1: Find the average cost! Suppose we have an array containing the costs of various foods. Find the average cost of the food!
You can use a for loop to go through the array! Remember, the average of a list is the total divided by the number of items
Task 2: Sorting an array! The cost of each item in the menu is all over the place!</description></item></channel></rss>