<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blocks: Create music with EarSketch on Nuevo Foundation Workshops</title>
    <link>/javascript-blocks-earsketch/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blocks: Create music with EarSketch on Nuevo Foundation Workshops</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 11:45:38 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/javascript-blocks-earsketch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Music Basics</title>
      <link>/javascript-blocks-earsketch/music-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>/javascript-blocks-earsketch/music-basics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;basics-first-a-few-things-about-music&#34;&gt;Basics first. A few things about music.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-music&#34;&gt;What is Music?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikiversity.org/wiki/Introduction_to_music&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Music&lt;sup&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;glyphicon glyphicon-new-window&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA; is the chronological organisation of sounds; that is, making certain sounds at certain times, which make melodic, rhythmic and harmonic sense. The first, most basic concept, is keeping the sounds &amp;ldquo;in time&amp;rdquo;. This leads us to some of the first few musical concepts: beat, rhythm, duration &amp;amp; tempo.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beat&lt;/strong&gt; is the regular pulse which provides a &lt;code&gt;timeline&lt;/code&gt; for the rhythm to anchor itself to.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rhythm&lt;/strong&gt; is essentially repeated patterns of long or short, stressed or unstressed sounds or silences which fit into the main beat.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Duration&lt;/strong&gt; is the length of notes or sounds or silences which facilitate the rhythm.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tempo&lt;/strong&gt; is the speed at which a piece of music is played.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with Earsketch</title>
      <link>/javascript-blocks-earsketch/getting-started-earsketch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>/javascript-blocks-earsketch/getting-started-earsketch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/EarSketch&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;EarSketch&lt;sup&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;glyphicon glyphicon-new-window&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA; is a free educational programming environment developed at Georgia Institute of Technology. We will be composing music using EarSketch today.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To make music, click on the below button to open Earsketch in a new tab.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;my-2 mx-4 btn btn-info&#34; href=&#34;https://earsketch.gatech.edu/earsketch2/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Launch Earsketch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;After opening the webpage, you may see the following welcome screen. Press &amp;ldquo;skip&amp;rdquo; to skip the tour - we will go over all the necessary steps below.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;../img/screenshot-skip-tour.png&#34; height=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Now, let&amp;rsquo;s get started. Click on &lt;em&gt;Scripts&lt;/em&gt; icon on the left menu bar and select &lt;em&gt;+ New Script&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;../img/screenshot-new-script.png&#34; height=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Enter &lt;em&gt;myjam&lt;/em&gt; (or any other name you wish) as the name of your script, and change the programming language to &lt;em&gt;JavaScript&lt;/em&gt;. Click on the &lt;em&gt;Create&lt;/em&gt; button to create your script (the file where your code will be placed).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;../img/screenshot-new-myjam.png&#34; height=&#34;200&#34;/&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, click on the gear icon, and select &amp;ldquo;Blocks mode&amp;rdquo;. Your screen should now look like this.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;../img/screenshot-setup-complete.png&#34; height=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;notices info&#34; &gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;p header-value=&#34;Info&#34;&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;recommended-for-teachers---overview-of-earsketch&#34;&gt;Recommended for Teachers - Overview of EarSketch&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please take a look at overview of EarSketch before you start with the class. It is important to know how to navigate back and forth in the UI.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activity 1 - Set tempo &amp; add sounds</title>
      <link>/javascript-blocks-earsketch/activity-1-set-tempo-add-sounds/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>/javascript-blocks-earsketch/activity-1-set-tempo-add-sounds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s take a closer look at the pre-existing code and understand what it means.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;../img/screenshot-setup-complete.png&#34; height=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;setTempo()&lt;/code&gt; function allows you to set the overall project tempo. Tempo is the speed at which a piece of music is played. Changing a project&amp;rsquo;s tempo allows for different styles of music to be created. Try changing the tempo of your &lt;code&gt;setTempo&lt;/code&gt; function by changing the number in the block and see what happens! Please make sure it is a number between 45-220. Below are some suggestions for tempos you can use.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activity 2 - Make a song!</title>
      <link>/javascript-blocks-earsketch/activity-2-make-a-song/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>/javascript-blocks-earsketch/activity-2-make-a-song/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now that you have learned how to add sounds to Earsketch, let&amp;rsquo;s try and make a song! You should already have one audio clip in Earsketch, but songs are made up of various instruments, so we need to add more audio clips.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add another &lt;code&gt;fitMedia()&lt;/code&gt; block.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Find an audio clip you would like to add to your current song and insert it under the &lt;code&gt;sound&lt;/code&gt; parameter.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;track&lt;/code&gt; parameter should be a unique number. This will allow us to place our sounds on different tracks. Having different sounds on different tracks allows us to maintain organization of our sounds and play different sounds at the same time. Example: If the first &lt;code&gt;fitMedia()&lt;/code&gt; call is on track 1, the second &lt;code&gt;fitMedia()&lt;/code&gt; call should be on track 2.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Complete the rest of the parameters.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Repeat these steps until you have four different audio sounds in your song.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Your code should now look something like this:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activity 3 - Add effects to your song</title>
      <link>/javascript-blocks-earsketch/activity-3-add-effects-to-your-songs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>/javascript-blocks-earsketch/activity-3-add-effects-to-your-songs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;effects-in-earsketch&#34;&gt;Effects in EarSketch&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Effects&lt;/strong&gt; allows the producer to alter the sound of the audio clip into its own unique sound. Similar to how we used &lt;code&gt;fitMedia()&lt;/code&gt; to add new audio clips, we must use the &lt;code&gt;setEffect()&lt;/code&gt; function to define specific effects for each audio clip. It is important to note that multiple effects can be placed on the same track. This allows for the producer to combine multiple effects together. Earsketch has many effects built-in. To reference all the effects, visit this &lt;a href=&#34;https://earsketch.gatech.edu/earsketch2/#?curriculum=5-1-0&amp;amp;language=python&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;link&lt;sup&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;glyphicon glyphicon-new-window&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA; and make sure &lt;em&gt;Curriculum&lt;/em&gt; pane is selected in the navigation bar.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activity 4 - Use effects to fade in</title>
      <link>/javascript-blocks-earsketch/activity-4-use-effects-to-fade-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>/javascript-blocks-earsketch/activity-4-use-effects-to-fade-in/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now that you have one effect in your song, let&amp;rsquo;s try to fade in the introduction of our song.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In activity 3, we used &lt;code&gt;setEffect&lt;/code&gt; function to apply an effect to a specific track for the entire duration of the song, but what if you only want a specific section of your song to have an effect? Use the &lt;code&gt;setEffect&lt;/code&gt; function with more parameters!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;../img/screenshot-seteffect2.png&#34; height=&#34;30&#34;/&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;startValue&lt;/code&gt;: The starting value applied to the parameter&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;start&lt;/code&gt;: The measure at which the starting value is set&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;endValue&lt;/code&gt;: The ending value of the parameter&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;end&lt;/code&gt;: The measure at which the ending value is set&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This version of the &lt;code&gt;setEffect&lt;/code&gt; allows for us to perform &lt;em&gt;automation&lt;/em&gt; on a specific piece of our song. Automation is a way to change the value of an effect over time. One use of automation is to make a song fade in or fade out. To do so, we must adjust the &lt;strong&gt;GAIN&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;parameter&lt;/code&gt;&amp;rsquo;s volume in the &lt;strong&gt;VOLUME&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;effectType&lt;/code&gt; over time. For example, if we define our &lt;code&gt;startValue&lt;/code&gt; at -60 db and our &lt;code&gt;endValue&lt;/code&gt; at 0db, it will sound like our song is fading in over time. To adjust the starting point and length of the effect, specify the &lt;code&gt;start&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;end&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
