<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Adafruit: Musical Fruit Programming on Nuevo Foundation Workshops</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/adafruit/</link><description>Recent content in Adafruit: Musical Fruit Programming on Nuevo Foundation Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/adafruit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Components</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/adafruit/the-components/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/adafruit/the-components/</guid><description>The components we will use for the project are listed below. Make sure you have all of these before starting:
One Adafruit USB-C to USB cord 2 alligator clip wires, any colors Two oranges</description></item><item><title>Building the DJ station</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/adafruit/building-the-dj-station/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/adafruit/building-the-dj-station/</guid><description>Hooking up the oranges Grab an orange and one of your wires. Open up one of the alligator clips and insert the bottom half into the orange, leaving the top part of the clip on the outside. This is easiest to do if you insert it in the middle of the bottom of the orange. The same spot where you’d start peeling if you were going to eat the orange.</description></item><item><title>Creating the Program</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/adafruit/creating-the-program/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/adafruit/creating-the-program/</guid><description>Open your favorite internet browser (such as Edge, Firefox, Google Chrome, Internet Explorer), and go to https://aka.ms/oranges. Your screen should look like this:
Defining the Variables Today we are going to be using oranges to tell our Adafruit when to make noise. The first thing we need to do is give the computer a name for each orange and where to look for what they are saying. We do the first part by defining a variable.</description></item><item><title>Downloading your program</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/adafruit/downloading-your-program/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/adafruit/downloading-your-program/</guid><description>At the bottom of your workspace you should see this bright pink download button next to the name of your program. You can name your program anything, here it’s called adafruit_musicalfruit. Click on the download button.
You should see a window popping up, asking where to save your file. It should default to the Downloads folder, if not, navigate to your downloads folder and save the file there.
Now you can plug your USB cable into the computer.</description></item><item><title>Answer Key - Adafruit</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/adafruit/answer-key/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/adafruit/answer-key/</guid><description>Setup In summary:
The two alligator clips should be clipped into the surface of the oranges. The other side of the clips should be on the A1 and A2 inputs on the adafruit. The USB should be plugged in to the adafruit, but not into the computer. After setup, the oranges and adafruit should look like this:
Solution Solution - advanced (with lights) How it Works</description></item></channel></rss>