<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hashmaps: The Delivery on Nuevo Foundation Workshops</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-datastructures/hashmaps/</link><description>Recent content in Hashmaps: The Delivery on Nuevo Foundation Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 13:24:17 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-datastructures/hashmaps/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-datastructures/hashmaps/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-datastructures/hashmaps/introduction/</guid><description>-- A hashmap is a table that holds a collection of key-value pairs. It &amp;ldquo;maps&amp;rdquo; numerous keys to their respective values. A hashmap is very similar to a dictionary. In a dictionary, you might want to look up a definition for a certain word. You simply look up the keyword in the dictionary and by doing so, you can get the definition attached to that keyword. The dictionary maps words (the &amp;ldquo;keys&amp;rdquo;) to their definition (the &amp;ldquo;values&amp;rdquo;).</description></item><item><title>Examples</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-datastructures/hashmaps/examples/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-datastructures/hashmaps/examples/</guid><description>-- Hashmaps A hashmap can store items in key/value pairs and you can assign those pairs to different types such as Strings or ints.
As usual, to create a HashMap, you will have to import the HashMap class like so.
import java.util.HashMap; // will import HashMap HashMap&amp;lt;String, String&amp;gt; addresses = new HashMap&amp;lt;String, String&amp;gt;(); In this case, we created a HashMap called addresses which stores keys of String type and values of String type.</description></item><item><title>Problem 1: Hashing</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-datastructures/hashmaps/problem-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 13:24:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-datastructures/hashmaps/problem-1/</guid><description>-- Task 1: Using Hashmap to organize data It&amp;rsquo;s a party! A customer has a big birthday party for more than 20 people! Everyone has their own order. To keep the mass order organized, you decide to create a hashmap of Strings. The birthday girl&amp;rsquo;s name is Isabella, but her name is lost in the list. Can you figure out what Isabella ordered?
Do you remember the hashmap methods? Look at example order below!</description></item><item><title>Problem 2: Making your own menu!</title><link>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-datastructures/hashmaps/problem-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 11:45:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://nuevofoundation.github.io/workshops/java-datastructures/hashmaps/problem-2/</guid><description>-- Task 1: Making Menu A new member of Nuevo Eats is struggling to create their own menu. Help create the menu! Each item should have a header (e.g. appetizer, Main dish, sides, drinks, etc.) as well as a price and name of the food. Be creative and make it how you want your Neuvo Eats to look!
What data structures do you want to use? Be creative! What are some of your favorite dishes?</description></item></channel></rss>